PAUL: Yeah, hello everyone, am I audible? Please let me know in the chats.
PAUL: Yes, guys.
PAUL: Alright, thanks for the confirmation.
PAUL: Good morning, everyone.
PAUL: Alright, so today we will continue with our discussion.
PAUL: With respect to the project hotel now, so in the last week we have done, so for everybody, I hope it is executing. Please let me know.
PAUL: Alright, so just wait, let me… Just get the window…
PAUL: This is such top 3.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Okay, so whatever I have discussed in the last class, so in this particular repo, I have pushed it.
PAUL: Okay, I'm sharing the link, if anybody new, whoever is joining.
PAUL: for them.
PAUL: Okay, so I've shared the GitHub link.
PAUL: And, I think we have done…
PAUL: only till, that part, where we have only executed our…
PAUL: The core functionalities of the app.
PAUL: Today's discussion will be around So, let me just take this one…
PAUL: Okay, so today we will be to, continue the project.
PAUL: Today, the first thing, Landsmith integration that will be working, then building the Docker image.
PAUL: Then, the AWS setup. Okay, so I've not mentioned here the AWS setup, so that will also come.
PAUL: I hope everybody has an AWS account. Multiple times I've repeated last week before that also.
PAUL: Yes, we will carry from exactly from where we left. Okay, that AWS setup, then…
PAUL: For continuous integration, GitHub Action will you be using? Okay, and finally, for deployment, AWS app runner that I'll be using, okay?
PAUL: And probably, like, once we have completed our project, then we will move ahead with another, framework, which is basically the Llama Index.
PAUL: Okay, so today, it's all about integration of services. So, initially, we will start with Langsmith. In the last class, we have already done for Langsmith. Okay, so… let's open Langsmith, and everybody, I think they… you guys have the environment variables in your .env. Please do have a check.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, let me just open… This one, alright…
PAUL: gitignore. Okay, so probably in your, .environment file, I hope everybody has done the setup.
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Yes or no. Have you guys done the setup?
PAUL: Have you added it in your .env below?
PAUL: Please do have it checked.
PAUL: No, nothing. And Thursday, nothing we have discussed with respect to project.
PAUL: Everybody, please have a check, take your time. Okay, and from here, you will be getting this information. So, for example, let me go back here, okay?
PAUL: Alignment.
PAUL: Okay, so…
PAUL: this part with respect to tracing, you have to click on this option. First, click on Tracing, and then click on this option of New Project. So once you click here, you'll be getting all the environment variables which are required.
PAUL: I know that, OpenAI API key, I think, previously, if you're working with Gemini, that is also fine.
PAUL: But, these four lines are important. Okay, so please paste them in your .env.
PAUL: Okay, and once you guys have given me the confirmation.
PAUL: Then again, I will just execute the app.
PAUL: Only you need to keep it in the ENV. The rest of the code, I think it's already there. So, if you go to your app.
PAUL: Okay, and here, if I check my main.py, so here, we are loading the environment settings. So automatically, it will be recognized.
PAUL: How to check endpoint? Which endpoint?
PAUL: Please share the Langsmith URL. Just do a simple Google search. I think everybody can write Langsmith and hit enter.
PAUL: Landsmith?
PAUL: And simply, like,
PAUL: I think it's not for me, already the link is there, but simply do a linesmith Sign up.
PAUL: Okay, so smith.lanchen.com. This is the official website from where you can do a simple sign-up. I'm sharing the link in the chat.
PAUL: Pass it in .env file, guys.
PAUL: Okay, just be sure you are clicking on Tracing and From Tracing to New Project.
PAUL: Let me change the name inside ENV. Okay, this time I will go with the…
PAUL: So we'll add a new project name, please.
PAUL: And, the ENV, you will be getting it from your settings, so… If you go to Settings…
PAUL: You can click on API Keys, okay, and from API Keys.
PAUL: You can breathe.
PAUL: do that.
PAUL: That is the original Ripple.
PAUL: Yes, right now, 1-22 tracing, yes, simple tracing, we'll be doing right now.
PAUL: Once you have executed it, the next thing.
PAUL: So, let me just get mine.
PAUL: Terminal… okay, I will just do a source.phng activate.
PAUL: Then comes your… UVCon server.
PAUL: So once you have configured your ENV file.
PAUL: With this, four options of landsmith tracing, okay, then we will test that the tracing is working or not.
PAUL: Yes, yes, simply. Like, if you have already done it in the last class.
PAUL: It's fine. If somebody has not done it, please do it. That's why I've shared the last class repolling, that we have worked on.
PAUL: It's fine. Like, I'm using the Europe region, you might use the North America. Only two regions are available.
PAUL: Project name, you can give anything. Project name, you can pass anything.
PAUL: Okay, so it will be automatically created.
PAUL: I think everybody has done it by this time.
PAUL: Yes, so… I will click on Tracing, new project, copy these things.
PAUL: So once you have copied, the only, information which is not available is your API key. That API key, get it from your settings.
PAUL: Click on API Keys, Okay, and plus API key. So, update the API key, that's the only thing.
PAUL: Alright, so let me start executing.
PAUL: So, right now, I will just, start back the UVCon server.
PAUL: Alright, I can see that the application has started successfully. Now, let me see… okay, alright.
PAUL: Pretty print. Let me just open the Swagger UI.
PAUL: Okay, I've added two times slash.
PAUL: Okay, so let me test a query and let me see that whether… because a new project will be created based on the environment name that you have passed here. Always remember.
PAUL: So, whatever the name that you have passed in your .env file, so based on that, a new project will be created. But here, I have just given a name rack viewer production class system. Okay, so four major words. I will trace that.
PAUL: Alright, so here I do have… let me drag the query part, whether everything is working or not.
PAUL: Evaluation, let me just remove it for now.
PAUL: Okay, and let me see whether it's working or not.
PAUL: Using Langsmith, I'm just doing a simple tracing, so once I get the results, I'll be showing you exactly.
PAUL: Okay, now this was the question which was asked, and based on that, I do have the result, the detection accuracy.
PAUL: Okay, so based on my data, the PDF that I have uploaded, so I'm getting a correct result. Now, let's get back to Lancemith.
PAUL: Okay, so now you can see that automatically the project will be available.
PAUL: Please do have a check. So right now, as you saw that, I added the system, okay? And here, you'll be getting all your traces.
PAUL: So, two, main operations that happened. So, on top of that, so the vector store retriever.
PAUL: Okay, and the runnable sequence. So, if you click on any of them.
PAUL: you'll be getting what is the input and what is the output. This was the main purpose, and what was the main, execution time that it took for the retrieval part, and then again, through chat Gemini, what was the time that has taken. So, all this information that you'll be getting.
PAUL: So, this is a simple tracing. There are other multiple tools also. So, Langsmith is always easy to integrate whenever we are working with the LandChain ecosystem. So, for that, I have used. Later on, I might switch to OPEC or some other.
PAUL: Saurav Verma is asking, kindly share the command for running the Fast API. I think everybody is familiar with the command.
PAUL: It's simple UVCon.
PAUL: app mani.
PAUL: Reload. In the last class, I have already discussed about this command.
PAUL: is the way of starting your Ubigon server.
PAUL: Please do have a check, everyone, that the Langsmith integration is working fine or not.
PAUL: Yes, generating production for every query, if you want to do that, it's a good practice to use trac. There are multiple tools. For now, Langsmith is the easiest one to work with.
PAUL: Please do have a checked…
PAUL: So, I think it should be up and working. The integration is simple and easy. You just need to keep it in your .env.
PAUL: Okay, and just be sure, because most of the times I know, as you will be passing the load. load underscore dot env from the package, python.env, so automatically it will be detected. Please let me know for how many of you it is working, and you can,
PAUL: actually look into any type of queries that you are asking. Please do check. Working, working.
PAUL: Alright, Rahul check, because, see, there is no other integration or any symbol. You have to keep it in the ENV file, and it should be up and working.
PAUL: Okay, for most of you, it's working, few people are getting some errors, okay?
PAUL: It's not errors, some people are telling you it's not getting recalplation. Please check the environment. Load.env.
PAUL: sometimes I have seen that, generally, this load, you can keep this part directly when you are actually starting your app, so here also you can pass it.
PAUL: If you feel that it is missing.
PAUL: Okay, so here also you can do that simple test.
PAUL: If it is not getting recognized, this is the only thing, because automatically it will be picked up. Nothing that I can do from my side.
PAUL: Mantaj, what is the purpose of pushing the information? So, if somebody is using, you need somewhere to look into your traces. What was the exact response? That's why.
PAUL: Tracing everybody uses.
PAUL: In other systems, for example.
PAUL: entire thing. I think in production, how many of you are using Sentry or something like Datadog?
PAUL: Yes, Century. Anybody's using Centric?
PAUL: Widely used in production.
PAUL: For general software programming. Everybody is using it. Similarly, data roll.
PAUL: in AI applications, really to look into the trace and other things, like Landsmith. It's only based on AI. Now, the same thing, observability tool. The same thing that we are doing with Landsmith also.
PAUL: Landsmith has a lot of other things to do with, like working with data sets and annotations. Right now, we are not talking about that. Right now, my major focus is only towards the tracing part.
PAUL: New Relic is also good. I like New Relic. Yes, mine.
PAUL: New, because I majorly worked with New Relic and Centric.
PAUL: Lesser with Datadog.
PAUL: how will the tracing happen? Automatically, the integration happens, Muta, sir. You have to just keep it in your ENV file. So, based on that, automatically, it picks up where your retriever store.
PAUL: and your, chain gets caught. On top of those two operations, like, anything that comes around in the output, you'll be getting the traces.
PAUL: So, if I show you my trace, so simply you can see here two instances are coming.
PAUL: Okay, so the first one was the vector store.
PAUL: Okay, and right here, based on the documents that I am getting, okay, from the VDB results.
PAUL: Okay, so these are the vector retriever results that I have.
PAUL: And similarly, for the other one. So, two major, things that I want to look into, exactly what is the content that is getting retripped, and finally, the response from the LL. Okay, so that's why only two traces…
PAUL: which are required, I think, at any point of time in RAD, two traces are required.
PAUL: So automatically that becomes… length fields is also good.
PAUL: Open the project, so just click on Tracing, and automatically you will see the project that you have created.
PAUL: Abhijit.
PAUL: Yes, there is an interceptor.
PAUL: Within the Langsmith call.
PAUL: Arise AI, no. Arise AI, again, like, it's a complete suit.
PAUL: And a few things that can be done in Arise AI also.
PAUL: Majorly for evaluation, and even for observability, you can use the rights, that is also fine.
PAUL: Abhijit, so right now, I'm only looking into two traces, the vector store, okay, and the chain call. Only those two outputs. Right now, there is no such hierarchy. Only two operations that automatically gets detected.
PAUL: Yes. Right now, everyone will be having some free limits. After that, you need to, get into a paid plan.
PAUL: I hope… please let me know, can I continue?
PAUL: Alright, so I hope the integration is done. It's simple.
PAUL: just pass to the environment file, and then start your app server. Now, in the next step, what I have.
PAUL: Okay, because our Landsmith integration is done, so we can do the tracing based on any type of question that I'm asking. Okay, then comes the AWS setup. So, in this particular AWS setup.
PAUL: I think the first thing that you need to create is an IAM user.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Once you have created the IAM user, the next thing
PAUL: will be setting up your CLI.
PAUL: setting up AWS CLI. How many have AWS CLI in your system?
PAUL: If you don't have, you need to download it.
PAUL: once the AWS CLI setup is done, I think…
PAUL: For now, two things. So, first of all, let's open AWS.
PAUL: Okay, I think in which account I have my AWS… Oh, God.
PAUL: EWF from Seoul. I have to log in. Okay, everybody, please log in to your main accounts.
PAUL: If you don't have… Please… log into your AWS accounts.
PAUL: Okay, let me get my authentication code.
PAUL: Authenticator…
PAUL: Alright guys, so please do log into your AWS accounts and AWS CLI download, let me check which page it has.
PAUL: Okay, alright, now this is the official page, I'm sharing it in the chat, just click on the link, okay, and based on your operating system.
PAUL: That you can do the installation.
PAUL: If I've shared the link, the official one, so according to your operating system, please do the installation.
PAUL: Okay, and once you have done it.
PAUL: the installation of the CLI, you can do the verification, so if I try to open here, like, AWS-conversion.
PAUL: Okay, he will be getting output something like this.
PAUL: Oof.
PAUL: I think for Mac users, it's, easy. You have to just do brief install.
PAUL: AWS CLI.
PAUL: Okay, so for Mac.
PAUL: The GUI installer, the command line installer is also there. So directly, the commands are available. Please do use that. I think for Windows, it's much easier. They do have a .exc available, the .ex file, yes, the MSI file is available. Directly, you can download it, and please install it in your system.
PAUL: If you have your AWS CLI up and running, Krishna, nothing. That's the only thing. It should be in your system. Take 2 minutes, please do the installation, and from your terminal, please try to have a check.
PAUL: Like, AWS hyphen hyphen version.
PAUL: Yes, in the comment prompt.
PAUL: You have to check this one. In every system, it will work.
PAUL: I missed the part, can you show once again? I've already shared the link for this. Again, I'm sharing. Please download the AWS CLI.
PAUL: Okay, according to your operating system, so all the major operating systems are listed here.
PAUL: I think you people majorly will be in Windows. In Windows, it's easy. So directly, the link is here. Please download the MSI file and do the installation. In Mac, it's free to install AWS CLI.
PAUL: And even for, Linux…
PAUL: command line, okay, first call, okay, now, these three commands that you need to run for Linux.
PAUL: So please, I think most of the students will be having AWS CLI in your system, but please take 2 minutes and complete this part.
PAUL: This is the continuation part, Krishna.
PAUL: Command prompt, I prefer.
PAUL: Like, Sylvan is asking, can I run in Windows PowerShell or Command from? This is a MSF file, double-click, double-click installation.
PAUL: Once the installation part is done, please let me know, like, for how many of you it is done.
PAUL: Just download the file and double-click in Windows.
PAUL: Next, next, and the installation will be done.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: This is a one-time task going forward in every project that we might need it.
PAUL: Okay, so once the installation is done, please do the verification.
PAUL: From your CMD. In Windows, sometimes a restart might be required, or any other thing, the problem can be there. Okay, so please do have a check based on your system.
PAUL: Alright, fine, it's, in your case, it's EXC, RM, alright, not an issue.
PAUL: Let me know, can I proceed?
PAUL: Because the installation is just a small part.
PAUL: Alright, so let's proceed ahead with the next part.
PAUL: So, go to IAM, and create a new user.
PAUL: Go to IAMs, go to the user section, and create a new user.
PAUL: As simple as that. So, for example, I'm creating a user.
PAUL: Alright, so I've given the name, I will just do a next.
PAUL: Then comes attach policies directly. So, initially, you can go ahead with the admin access, but, specifically, like, the two main services that I'll be using.
PAUL: One is, the ECR, where I'll be saving my Docker images, ECR part.
PAUL: So, somewhere around, I think, ECR full access you'll be getting.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just check the ECR container registry, I will write it.
PAUL: Okay, so as you can see, I'm going ahead with this one.
PAUL: So, I'm just sharing the name of the permissions.
PAUL: Here's do it in Azure.
PAUL: Okay, if you want, you can do it, I have no restrictions. I am doing it in AWS, so based on that, you have to change the code.
PAUL: In CD part. Okay, I'll be telling about it. If you want to use a different cloud, okay, you have to do some changes with the script.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Okay, alright, I've selected the wrong one. Actually, I need the container registry, yes, this one.
PAUL: Then, I need the app runners, AAPP app runner.
PAUL: I think AWS AppRunner. So, two major services I'll be using for hosting our application, that will be using AppRunner, and the other service where I'll be pushing my Docker image.
PAUL: Okay, so for that, I'll be using ECR.
PAUL: So, simply, you can check, I'm sharing again the name here. Copy.
PAUL: Alright, so this is one permission, I think, next.
PAUL: Alright, and this is the other one. Container Registry Full Access.
PAUL: Okay, so here I have 3 permissions.
PAUL: So based on that, you can also pass the permissions, and I will just create the user.
PAUL: The few people are telling you where is the IM option, search here. Search, search.
PAUL: There is a search option, just click there, I am.
PAUL: Okay, so just wait, I will create. Search here for IAM, you will be getting, see, IAM, access managed to AWS Resources.
PAUL: Okay, so once you click on iron.
PAUL: You'll be getting an EY, so from here, users will be coming. Left-hand side panel, click on users.
PAUL: And right now, I've just created one user.
PAUL: Now I need the access case for this particular…
PAUL: user that I have created. Please let me know. For everybody, it's simple, 2-3 clicks are there.
PAUL: Not required tags.
PAUL: Tags are not required for now.
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: The first part is done, creating the user.
PAUL: It's simple, two clicks.
PAUL: You need time? One minute.
PAUL: Alright, take 2 minutes, do that.
PAUL: Yes, for every cloud account, you need to set up the payment part.
PAUL: Which region are you using, I think.
PAUL: U.S. East on the North Virginia region for now.
PAUL: the default region.
PAUL: I am not planning to change. If you want a different region, you can do that. And I know that, these two major applications, it can be accessed in any region, so Mumbai region is also fine.
PAUL: No, Docker part, I will be doing it. First, do these things, then I will come to the part with respect to Docker.
PAUL: Alright, now, once you have created the users, you have to click on the security credentials, and please get your access keys. So, from here, you'll be getting the access keys. Create access key. Just click on create, then you have to click on the command line interface.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: I understand, and next.
PAUL: Once you have clicked on next.
PAUL: Then click on Create Access Pey.
PAUL: Okay, and please download the .csv file, because we'll be using these secrets.
PAUL: In some other places also, okay? So please download the .csv file.
PAUL: How much you have to pay right now? I think for AppRunner, it totally depends for how much time you are doing the app execution, if you just delete it right now.
PAUL: Okay, there are only mud charges. Generally, like, my billing comes less than $1 for this stuff.
PAUL: Everyone, please let me know, have you created the access keys for your user?
PAUL: Simple 3 steps are there.
PAUL: Okay, click on your user, go to the security credentials, click on that. There will be an option of getting your access keys. Okay, please click on create access key, and download the .csv file.
PAUL: Tags not required for now.
PAUL: Yes, Pan, it will ask.
PAUL: Pan, credit card, yes, those things.
PAUL: These things I've already told you in the last task, please do the setup and make your AWS account ready.
PAUL: Alright, now, the services that I'll be using, one is the ECR, the Elastic Container Registry, Okay.
PAUL: So, this particular service.
PAUL: So here, right now, I do have, reports, but in your case, it will be blank. So, Amazon ECR is the name of the service.
PAUL: And I think everybody knows about repos. Repos are basically where we save our
PAUL: Docker artifacts. So, sometimes it is called as artifact registry also, the term which is widely used.
PAUL: Okay, so artifact registry. So, here, we will be pushing our Docker image. So, here, we have to create a repo, and within that repo, we'll be keeping our image.
PAUL: Right now, if I show you, so you can see here, like, images will be available.
PAUL: So, similarly, the open source version, you have your Docker Hub, the same thing that you do. Similarly, in GCP, you have your artifact registry.
PAUL: Just a similar service. In every cloud, these things are available.
PAUL: Mitesh is asking what use case to select for access key? What use case? You don't have to select any use case.
PAUL: There was no use case which was asked to me.
PAUL: And right now, see, this is the default region that I'll be using. Okay, so US-East hyphen 1. So just be sure, whichever region you are selecting.
PAUL: So… and just do a verification that you are in the correct region.
PAUL: Rajat Karna is asking how to add the policies. Already shown that part.
PAUL: Again, I'm showing you.
PAUL: I aim… Once you go to the user part, okay, create user, parse any name.
PAUL: Okay, then click on next, click on Attach Policies directly, so search here. First of all, like, the admin access, just get this one. And, like, two services, because by admin access, most of the things will be accessible to you, everything, like…
PAUL: But, the major services, because in production it's a bad practice to use it. So, here I will be selecting your container.
PAUL: You can see here, Amazon Elastic, so this is one of them that I need. I'm sharing the name here.
PAUL: So this is the full access, and then comes your app runner.
PAUL: AppRunner is the service using which I'll be hosting the application. You can see here, AWS AppRunner Full Access. Just click on next, three things automatically will come, done. Create user.
PAUL: I hope.
PAUL: This part is done for everyone.
PAUL: Okay, because, really, inside ECR you don't, need, we will configure it from the local one. Okay, and as you can see here, build and run production web applications at scale.
PAUL: To…
PAUL: I think… let me open. Okay, now this is the service, and here you can actually look into the compute cost.
PAUL: Okay, so I think in my case, I'll be using a 2GB RAM with a vCPU, it will work really good.
PAUL: Please let me know once the configuration is done.
PAUL: Because then we will be doing the local setup. Here, nothing you have to really do. I'm just showing you the services exactly. This is a fully managed service that comes from AWS, and it becomes easier. Later on, like, once we have explored in our first project, then probably in other projects we'll be using Fargate, somewhere, he came.
PAUL: But for now, let's start with simple. We can use, like, EBS also, Elastic Beanstack is also there, AWS Lambda is also there. Okay.
PAUL: There is nothing to show in the easier part. I have not done any configuration on Nirut.
PAUL: Okay, so two services, ECR and AppRunner, that I'm using.
PAUL: Madhasar is Jenkins used in typical productions? Yes, we can work with Jenkins.
PAUL: But, majorly, I feel that every organization is keeping their code in GitHub, so I prefer GitHub Actions much more for the CI part.
PAUL: AppRunner is similar to Cloud Run in GCP, characterically.
PAUL: Generally, in Azure also, you have that web app.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, just very similar services that is being used.
PAUL: Alright, now,
PAUL: Two services, I hope for everybody this is configured. Now, just go to your terminal, and do AWS Configure. You have to write this one.
PAUL: Okay? AWS Configure.
PAUL: On-prem… yes, on-prem service, yeah, Jenkins Institute.
PAUL: I have used Jenkins, but really, the setup really takes so long. I feel that using GitHub Actions is always much better.
PAUL: If your code is in GitHub.
PAUL: Okay, so everyone, please do check the AWS configure part, okay, and hit enter. It will ask you the information that you have downloaded from the CSV file. Please pass it.
PAUL: Okay, so here you can see, it will ask for the access key. Once you have passed the access key, then it will ask for the
PAUL: I think,
PAUL: Secret access key. This information also you have in your CSV file. Please pass the information.
PAUL: Then comes the region. I am using US-East 1, the default one. Okay, and the output format, you can keep it none. Just hit enter. It will be blank for now.
PAUL: Everybody, please do the steps.
PAUL: Deepak, it will be available in your CSV file that you have downloaded.
PAUL: when you created the IAM user, then you created the security credentials, or basically the access keys, open that access key file, that CSV file, and from there, you'll be getting these two information of access key ID and secret access key. And the region name, please pass the region that you are using.
PAUL: I'm going slow only, Valadin. Okay. Otherwise, just take 5 minutes, do the setup.
PAUL: Simple click, click, click, everything from cloud interface that we are doing.
PAUL: Check, for example.
PAUL: For AppRunner, you can see right now, whenever you click a service like ECR or AppRunner, you will be getting it. For IAM users, that will be only the global section, so don't get confused.
PAUL: And by default, whenever you are creating a new account, most of the times it's not Virginia only.
PAUL: U.S. East 1.
PAUL: API secret queue, stool secret manager, nothing I have saved as secret manager, Raul.
PAUL: What should be the default output? Just hit enter. Just skip that part. Blank, blank.
PAUL: Which part?
PAUL: Do you want me to show again? Because I'm not using it till now, like, Secret Manager from AWS.
PAUL: Secret key… there is secret keys available in that CSV file that you have downloaded when you created the IAM user. For that, you created the access key. Please open that access key CSV file and access it.
PAUL: Okay, here I am…
PAUL: Users… okay, so for example, this user, if I go to security credentials.
PAUL: Click on access key, click on Command Line, click on the web recommendation, I understand, click on Access Key, download .csv file, done.
PAUL: Will you be using SageMaker? No, I won't be using SageMaker. Why I need SageMaker?
PAUL: Please do the configuration, and then please let me know that the local configuration is done.
PAUL: Because all the information, directly, we'll be getting it from there.
PAUL: No, why Pedrov, I believe? What is the purpose? There is no purpose over here.
PAUL: Neither I am working with Bedrock agents, neither I have taken the LLM from Bedrock. Then what is the purpose?
PAUL: We can run the command to confirm. Yes, you can always run AWS configure. Again, the command, no issue.
PAUL: Okay, you can always do the verification.
PAUL: Again, you can run it.
PAUL: I hope I've given enough time. No, no, no, no. AWS H3L is not required.
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: That is the spot done or not.
PAUL: With this part done, please let me know, everyone.
PAUL: Alright, now I will just open Notion, because I'll be pasting some commands. Okay, so I will update it in the Notion.
PAUL: Manually, I don't want to do it, everything click, click, so much times. It's better to go with a command line system, because my, now, local authentication is done. So, let me just open Notion. Okay, where is Notion?
PAUL: Okay, alright, the notion is we are already, I think.
PAUL: Perfect, so here, if you go directly, just click on the project one, okay, and here you have that. So here, I'll be passing some custom commands.
PAUL: So, slash, bold, let me just open. Okay, the first command that I'll be using is basically to create the ECR report, okay? Create a…
PAUL: ECR report.
PAUL: Okay, so you can take the command from Notion directly.
PAUL: So, let me just get the command.
PAUL: Okay, and even in the chat, I'll be pasting it.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the command using which you can create. Now, here, I have passed the name of the report. As you can see here.
PAUL: at Juventus system, you can pass anything, okay, whichever name that you want.
PAUL: Totally up to you. So if I take this command, I will go here.
PAUL: AWS ECR, create repository, the name of the repository that I have passed is QS System for now.
PAUL: Okay, so let's take something on top of that.
PAUL: And I will add.
PAUL: Hybrid at the end for now.
PAUL: Okay, so this is just a simple command. Once you have done the local authentication, you just need to execute this one.
PAUL: Okay, so let me execute this command.
PAUL: And right now, as you can see, that the RAGQ system, the ECR repository, has been created.
PAUL: Shankarajaudhury already. The notion link is shared with everyone.
PAUL: Please don't ask for the Notion link in every class. Once I have shared it, then again, why I told you guys to do the bookmark. I'm sharing the command in the chat.
PAUL: In Notion, I've already shared it.
PAUL: So I think if I go and click on View Website, I will just do a verification.
PAUL: So, here you can see the command is available. So, the things that you need to configure here, the repository name, whichever name that you want, please pass it, and probably the region. If you're in it using a different region, please pass that exact region name.
PAUL: Okay, repo created.
PAUL: Alright, now let's use that describe once. Okay, so…
PAUL: I can pause describe refer for a verification.
PAUL: Okay, AWS ECR Describe reports.
PAUL: So right now, I have, like, multiple reports, but I can actually see rack event system hybrid is available that I have used. Okay, so I know that it got created. So this particular command also, I'll be passing it in Notion.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: So, both the commands, I have passed it.
PAUL: the same thing that I have.
PAUL: Passed in the chat also.
PAUL: Okay, so I know that the repo is available. The next thing is, let's start working on the image part.
PAUL: Okay, so first of all, let me just start my Docker client.
PAUL: So, everyone, please start your Docker flight.
PAUL: I think for everybody the repo got created, please let me know. Because here, there is… if there is some issue, it means that you are passing something wrong with the AWS access key and the secret. That can be the main reason.
PAUL: Yes, please check. Abhisheh, when you look into the error, please read the error itself. It's an error occurred, invalid signature exception. It means that, simply, like, you need to pass the correct specification.
PAUL: Mmm, skip that part, Amit.
PAUL: Generally, I use it for my, verification.
PAUL: Alright, Gagandaev, I am running behind, please let me know all this option to select, creating. Please let me know all the options to select. I won't be going again, repeating.
PAUL: I've already waited.
PAUL: few minutes, and I'm giving enough time.
PAUL: I think this part is done, please let me know, can I proceed ahead with the next part?
PAUL: the repo part.
PAUL: The repo got created, and simply I've done the verification, and I can see that the repo has come.
PAUL: Should I wait?
PAUL: Pawan, totally your choice.
PAUL: Use AWS CLI, use Git Bash, anything.
PAUL: And just be sure, if it's an office system, okay, you might get blocked. Nothing that we can do.
PAUL: Okay? Just open your Docker, nothing. Just be sure, when you do, like,
PAUL: Docker, I think if I do a PS, nothing will come for me, but at least the Docker client is running in your system.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Docker is showing a new CMD grid.
PAUL: I think for everybody, this part is done. I've waited.
PAUL: Okay, Dig Bajar is asking, can you show me an AWS screen where I can find the reports? Just go to the service. Just click here, click on ECR,
PAUL: Classic Container Registry, and he will be seeing that the repo, the rags, keyword system hybrid. Here it will be available.
PAUL: Alright, if you are working with Portman, please look into that, okay?
PAUL: Alright, now the part. I think for everybody, this part is done.
PAUL: Now, I will proceed ahead with the next part. So, let's start working on the Docker image.
PAUL: So, first of all, for the docker, let me just create a new file.
PAUL: I think the file part is important, and I will get the script.
PAUL: Alright, I do have the script now, so let's get back to our IDE.
PAUL: Anti-gravity, alright.
PAUL: So, here… Alright, this is the plus.
PAUL: Just create a Docker file.
PAUL: Okay, and I will paste the content of Dockerfile here.
PAUL: Okay, so just wait, I will make a push.
PAUL: And then from the repo, get it.
PAUL: Okay, so in the GitHub, I have pushed the file, so it should be accessible to you.
PAUL: Please do have a check.
PAUL: I think for everybody, it should be accessible.
PAUL: If I show you here, you can see that the Dockerfile got pushed.
PAUL: Okay, use the Docker file.
PAUL: Doesn't matter, Amit, use this file, same content, go through the content at least.
PAUL: I think this, this time I'm using 3.13, the last one it might be 3.12, but really doesn't matter. In both the 3.12 and 3.13, it will work.
PAUL: Alright, let me know. So, once you got the Dockerfile, then I will start the discussion.
PAUL: for the Dockerfile.
PAUL: doc… yes, Docker command will be the same for every project.
PAUL: Somebody is saying I am unable to see the Docker file. Again, I'm sharing the link in the chat.
PAUL: Just do a simple refresh of the webpage and you can access it. I've shared the link also.
PAUL: Alright, so let's start with our discussion with the Dockerfile.
PAUL: Now,
PAUL: First of all, whenever we are working with a Docker, we need a base image. Okay, so for now, I'm using Python 3.13. You can use a Python 3.12. Really, with respect to images, there are no restrictions. If you want some other image, you can use it, because there are different variants.
PAUL: Now, coming through the parts, defining my work directory, exactly, like, where my project files will be there, what that I have defined, my work DIR, then executing few, scripts, like APTK. Now, these are based on TBN-based systems in Linux.
PAUL: So, APT gate update, I'm doing the update of the base image within that.
PAUL: And few other things, like build installation, and finally, I'm deleting few things to make the image much lighter. So, as you can see, RM, if, and RF within this. Now, these are common setups for every type of, I can say, Docker build when you are doing it.
PAUL: Now, the main thing is, we need the package. So, for that, we have the requirement.txt, where all the…
PAUL: packages are mentioned, and the idea is, within that particular Docker environment, I have to do the setup, so I'm just copying the file. So, from where source?
PAUL: requirement.txt, this is basically the source, and dot refers to the destination. Okay, and where is the destination? Your work directory.
PAUL: Then in the next step, setting up our Python environment.
PAUL: So, this is within the image, this is the environment through which you can get it. Right now, PythonM-VN. So, what we are doing?
PAUL: Creating the virtual environment, setting up the environment path through this. And finally, doing a no-catcher directory. Always remember, it's a good practice to use this no-catcher directory, and that way, there is no catching mechanism that happens. Otherwise, the size of the image will be bigger.
PAUL: Okay, now…
PAUL: Now, see, you can use different images also, but for now, I've kept the same image, because this is for, testing our initial CI build, this I have used. Similarly, for our production, I'm using, like, you can change the image for production, like, for different environments I've kept.
PAUL: Like, two separate image options. So that's why, again, the same thing for this particular image. Though it's a repeated stuff, the idea is that in the same Dockerfile, you can have two different types of stages. One only for the CI part, one only for the CD part.
PAUL: So, I gave the same setup. Now, it's a very good practice that not to execute anything from the root user. So, what I've done, I've just created a user. Now, the user that I've created, through which I'll be executing it.
PAUL: And the user that I'll be creating for that, I have passed. So right now, as you can see, app user. Okay, to this, I provide the ownership permission so that it can use it. Finally, I am doing a switch operation from the root user to the app user. Okay, setting up your environment variables within your Python.
PAUL: Now comes exposing the port, exactly in which port my application is running. I know in FastAPI, by default, the port will be always 8000.
PAUL: Okay, so you need to expose the code within your Docker.
PAUL: Then comes performing some health check. I know once a server will start, so using HTTP localhost slash health, I know this is the route. If you hit the route, you'll be getting the health information.
PAUL: Okay, so this is basically the health check part.
PAUL: And then finally, to start the application, the same command that we have executed, uvicon main app host, you have to pass your, like, 00, the local host part, and in which port the application will be running. So just be sure exactly the information that you are passing.
PAUL: is correct. If you want to change the port, you can change. There is no restriction in there. Just be sure herein, in both the places, the exposed port and this port should be the same.
PAUL: There is a single Docker file only, there are no two Docker files.
PAUL: Abhishek, those are Linux-based commands. If you are not familiar with Linux, nothing that I can do.
PAUL: Docker Compose, I'm not using Docker Compose.
PAUL: I don't have multiple containers right now, it's a single container.
PAUL: Now, common things that I've done, I've added nothing fancy in my Dockerfile. I've kept it very, very simple, and the things that we do in our normal practices.
PAUL: Please let me know, then I will start working on the Docker build.
PAUL: Rakesh Jassar is telling this part is not clear. What is not clear?
PAUL: Which part do you want me to explain?
PAUL: I'm just creating one image.
PAUL: I'm creating just one image.
PAUL: First of all.
PAUL: This is the build stage that I have taken. Here, I have selected my base image, then I have selected my working directory, a few Linux-based commands, because I know the core base package is based on Debian build.
PAUL: Then creating a virtual environment, setting up the path, doing the installation of the requirements.
PAUL: Now, you can use a different image for your production, so for that, I've just kept a separate path. So for this, if you don't want, simply you can delete everything from here.
PAUL: Okay, you can comment this part out. No restrictions in that. Now, once you are within your image, the idea is that you should not execute something from the root user. If you are executing something from the root user.
PAUL: It means that you are exposing some type of security vulnerability. Okay, so we don't want that, so we are just creating a user, we are giving the permission. Okay, we are changing the ownership, we are switching the user, and then we are actually executing our application through Vicon Main app.
PAUL: Pretty much simple Docker finding.
PAUL: Yes, the environment variables will come, no? I'll be passing them during the build.
PAUL: I'll be passing them during the build.
PAUL: Alright, let's start. I have wasted a lot of time.
PAUL: So, let's start here. Okay. Now, to do the build, I will just take, let's take, I think…
PAUL: docker run, please write the command by yourself, okay? So here, rack project class, I think I can take the…
PAUL: File name as this one, okay? So here, what I've done, docker run hyphen P,
PAUL: Then, I am doing a port mapping operation from 8000 to 8,000.
PAUL: Then comes… I'm selecting my .env file for now, so hyphenv file, and then I'm selecting the name of the image that I want.
PAUL: Please let me know. Okay, now, actually, this is the run command, I need the build command, just wait.
PAUL: Docker build… okay, hyphen T, this one.
PAUL: So right now, please do the build, first of all. Okay, I'm sharing the command. You can pass anything. This will be the name of the image. Okay, and let me just see whether I do have some images already, because I was testing it out previously. No, there is nothing in my local.
PAUL: Okay, so I will just do this…
PAUL: Let's do the build first, then I will do the run in the next part. I've shared the command.
PAUL: Okay, it will take some time.
PAUL: Alright, so this bat is done.
PAUL: Please do have a check, guys. Okay, so now if I go to Docker, images…
PAUL: Okay, you will see that the latest image is available, and the size is close to, like, 1GB that I have.
PAUL: In your case, it will take some time, so I will just wait 2 to 3 minutes, sign up. Because for me, it's picking up from the catcher, in your case, it will start from fresh. So, yes, the build will take time, so let's wait.
PAUL: Alright, the command in the Notion, I'm sharing it.
PAUL: Where is my Notion?
PAUL: Just be sure that the old instance of UVCon running, be sure you are closing it in your local app. So, I have just execute… completed this process.
PAUL: now I will start the part with respect to… so the build part is done for me. The next part is the execution. So, let me… just be sure, once the build is done, you are doing a verification with Docker images.
PAUL: Now, once this verification that you have done, the next thing is to make the run.
PAUL: From the project directory, everything I am doing from the project directory. Please look into my screen and look.
PAUL: the working directory.
PAUL: The command is exactly the same one that I have executed. How many of you are getting error in this one?
PAUL: Because I think this is a simple command, there is no such complications. Please do have it checked.
PAUL: Please let me know for how many of you the build is going on.
PAUL: Or, like it is done.
PAUL: the build is done, alright. If the build is done, then fine.
PAUL: Yes, it will take some time, just wait.
PAUL: Initially, one time, it's a thing. Okay, so it takes time, only once.
PAUL: Next, you… next time you will execute, everything will be picked up from the catcher.
PAUL: Dagbajay, after 15 minutes, we will do the break.
PAUL: Now, I will run the…
PAUL: application that I have, so the command that I have shared in Notion, just pick it up. Okay, so I think this is the one.
PAUL: Now, let's get back here.
PAUL: Okay, now in this docker run hyphen p, the port mapping part, here I am passing the .env selection and the rad project. So this command, I have already shared it in the Notion for
PAUL: whom it's up and working, please let me know. Okay, so if I just…
PAUL: do the execution of this. Okay, so I can see, yes, the UVCon server is running.
PAUL: Okay, now, yes, see, I am using 000. In Windows, sometimes in 0, you get an error. Please use the term localhost, or use 127.0.m. So, those are totally up to you. Based on your OS configuration settings, please do make those changes.
PAUL: Alright, now let me just check that this is working or not. I feel that it should work.
PAUL: So, I can see, yes, it is working.
PAUL: slash… Docs, let me go there.
PAUL: Alright, I can see my Docker is working fine. There is…
PAUL: No issue, let me just pass a… Query for now.
PAUL: Okay, even I will check, only two things are there. It should also be updated.
PAUL: So, let's say in the new update.
PAUL: Okay, I got the answer, so it is working here, and the landsmith, let me see the traces are coming or not. Yes, the traces are coming. So I know that, yes, in my local, everything is working, the Docker image is fine. The next step is basically to push the image to AWS ECR.
PAUL: Everybody, please check the application is up and working.
PAUL: how you are mapping your AWS project directory to… there is nothing to do… there is no mapping. It's simply, once you have installed AWS CLI, it can be accessed from anywhere.
PAUL: Invalid port 63322, I'm not using 63, please use 8000 put, as per the code that I have given.
PAUL: Deva is asking how git slash post API…
PAUL: portal you have launched, really. Like, just click on the URL which is provided.
PAUL: So, in my case, the URL was provided, this one, 0008000. After that, add the slash docs.
PAUL: Route, and you are good to go.
PAUL: Check your runtime error. In the runtime error directory, issues are coming. Please check that route.
PAUL: Everybody, please let me know the Docker build is done successfully. The first step. Once the build is done, then you will be executing the image, or basically you will run the image to make the container. So, if I just open…
PAUL: Not this one, just wait. I think, Ctrl-D.
PAUL: If I do a docker PS hyphen A, you will see that, yes, my Docker image is running after 3 minutes, okay, the command and the ports which are created. So, pretty much working.
PAUL: Okay, alright, the build stage, I know initially it will take some time.
PAUL: Even in our deployments also, it really takes a lot of time.
PAUL: Okay, so fine, take your time, not a hurry.
PAUL: Take your time. Do the setup. If you're getting some error, try to debug and try to resolve.
PAUL: That's true.
PAUL: I'm not using any directory static.
PAUL: Rohit, there is no directory called a static only.
PAUL: Please, guys, pick up the correct Dockerfile, at least, that is my expectation.
PAUL: Okay, check the URL. Pove when they run. Click on the URL, and add slash docs, you will get the Swagger UI.
PAUL: First of all, Where is static in my Dockerfile? Really, I'm not getting. I've shared the Dockerfile link.
PAUL: With respect to static, where there is static.
PAUL: Pick up the right Dockerfile at least.
PAUL: Where is the right Docker file?
PAUL: Let me just show you.
PAUL: I think it is there in…
PAUL: Okay, let me do the reload.
PAUL: check the Dockerfile that I have shared, at least check the time.
PAUL: 21 minutes of what I have shared. Please, just be sure you are using the correct Docker file.
PAUL: If you use something wrong, then you will get an error.
PAUL: There is… first of all, when you look into the error, just see, are there any static folder?
PAUL: It means that you were using a wrong image.
PAUL: Please at least look into your project directory structure, what is there.
PAUL: Take your time, look into the code, okay, and try to do the debug, because all the steps I've mentioned, just be sure, in your local machine, the Docker image has been tested successfully. Once it has been tested, then in the next step, I'll be pushing to ECR.
PAUL: Or actually, I'll be making the CI call in the next step. Automatically, everything will be done.
PAUL: There, I won't be updating.
PAUL: I have shared the repo, please use that repo.
PAUL: I have to take the continuation of the class, I cannot bring something out of the box.
PAUL: Let me know for how many of you it is done.
PAUL: For how many of you, the image is working in your local machine?
PAUL: Image created, alright, great. Once the image is created, please do execute it. The command, I have already shared it.
PAUL: Okay, so just be sure you are using the correct command.
PAUL: docker run hyphen P, already this is shared in your Notion, please do check Notion, and just be sure you are passing the .env file.
PAUL: It works in localhost. Alright, great. If it is working in localhost, that's the only thing. You need to do the verification in your local machine. The Docker image is working. If it is working fine, there are no issues, we will go for the next step.
PAUL: And check the query route rule for now. At least check the core part.
PAUL: Because I have only checked the query route, I have not checked the document upload, but if you want me, I can test it out there. I have not tested that one.
PAUL: So… just wait. Let me test it now.
PAUL: I think this is the one… Local horse… Let me just check.
PAUL: Everything is working fine.
PAUL: Alright, tested. The upload one is also working great. Now, the next step that comes.
PAUL: The process is pretty much simple, just check for everybody. I'm giving you 10 minutes more. Just do the verification, because in the next step, it's the part where we'll start the deployment phase.
PAUL: Just kill. Kill every server, and then just be sure it is working.
PAUL: Just kill the other servers.
PAUL: If you're not killing the, current running server in Docker, you will get an error.
PAUL: check with localhost. If you're on Windows, don't use 00. I don't, prefer so much. And Mac and Linux 00 really works out.
PAUL: Mmm, it should show.
PAUL: 00 slash 8000, where you were writing.
PAUL: 0, then more than 8,000 details.
PAUL: Alright, it's going to be 10, 27. Okay, so let's go for a break, and then we will do the…
PAUL: I will wait 5 minutes, then I will start the timer.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes.
PAUL: discussion I won't be doing right now.
PAUL: Discussion after the class.
PAUL: First image will be created, then the container. When you run the image, it becomes a container.
PAUL: Simple steps. Just go into Notion, and follow the steps.
PAUL: all the steps I have mentioned right here.
PAUL: Admin. Already done the document part.
PAUL: Yes, we'll be taking a break, Sangeet.
PAUL: for everyone, please do check. Local issues can be there, because when Docker comes system to system, issues can be there, plus at least do have a check.
PAUL: Mammoth? No. For… if you want to check the images, please use the command docker images.
PAUL: If you want to check the running containers, then docker ps hyphen A.
PAUL: Notion is not updated, somebody is telling.
PAUL: Notion is updated.
PAUL: Yes, that is the correct one, Kira.
PAUL: The day doesn't matter, go into the Project 1 section.
PAUL: I think you people should be smart. Click on this project, both the links are exactly the same.
PAUL: I have to just update this link. Just click here, you will be getting that.
PAUL: Alright, Saurabh, it's working for you, good.
PAUL: But all those routers getting internal and all.
PAUL: The route should be working, Harish.
PAUL: All the routes should be working.
PAUL: Please check the issue and try to debug it.
PAUL: For everybody, it should work.
PAUL: If you are getting error, some OS level.
PAUL: Complications can be there, so you need to resolve it.
PAUL: Already, I see, once we have checked the app is working in your local, then we'll come to the next phase of the deployment.
PAUL: It can take time, Satish.
PAUL: For everybody. For me also, the docker build command takes time.
PAUL: Just be sure you are using the correct Dockerfile that I have shared now.
PAUL: There is no command to check swaggerma. You have to open it from the URL by adding slash docs at the end.
PAUL: Selini Vasa, please use the correct Docker file.
PAUL: That I have shared.
PAUL: I will just add the Docker URL once more here, just wait.
PAUL: Where is San Diego?
PAUL: Just be sure you are using the correct Docker file.
PAUL: And I will build it in motion.
PAUL: I have added in Notion also the Docker file.
PAUL: you don't have to upload it in ECR.
PAUL: Just, we show the Docker image is working.
PAUL: Alright, let me start the timer.
PAUL: I'm giving you guys some time, please.
PAUL: Be sure you guys have sorted it out.
PAUL: Alright, if it is working, great. We'll move to the next part, which is the CI part.
PAUL: So, let's wait for 10 minutes, I'll be back in time.
PAUL: Alright guys, so I think by this time.
PAUL: For most of you, it should be up and working. If you are getting any errors, I will look into that during the doubts.
PAUL: Okay, Ushul is asking, last Saturday we use? That is the main one, but we have to do the continuation, no? So for that continuation, I'm using the class repo.
PAUL: That is the entire one.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: For Windows users, okay, sometimes 00,
PAUL: might not work, you can use localhost or 127.0.0.1. That's totally fine.
PAUL: Alright, now let's proceed ahead with the next step.
PAUL: So, Shane is asking, docker build hyphen T, alright, got installed image, now we have to run the image. Yes, you have to run the image, please use this particular command to run it.
PAUL: Alright, now the first part is done.
PAUL: Now, let's start with the next part. Now, here we'll be adding the CI part, the continuous integration, okay?
PAUL: So, based on my first project, there are a few things. Right now, I've just kept it much lighter this time.
PAUL: the CI part. Later on, you guys can do some modifications on top of that. So, let me just get the URL…
PAUL: Where is the URL?
PAUL: This is not there… Let me check Fagan, yes.
PAUL: I think this one… And this one, alright.
PAUL: Now, I will start, discussing, so exactly, like, whenever you are making your CI and CD pipelines. So, what are the things that you need to take care of? So, for now, for our CI integrations, which is basically the continuous integrations, I'll be using GitHub Actions.
PAUL: And, for that, I'll be sharing you the script.
PAUL: So, first of all, just focus on the flow of our CI CD, exactly what are the things that you need to keep in.
PAUL: So, first of all, like, once the code is pushed, like, automatically, once you have done the commit, the build should automatically start, okay? So, first of all, so this is a general format always, like, check out the code.
PAUL: Then setting up the Python environment, setting up your dependencies.
PAUL: Okay. Now, these options are totally optional, because it's not necessary, but in production, when you actually go, you have to use code letters, code formatters to check that everything is fine or not. Okay, so that's why rough and black data are used.
PAUL: Okay, so if you are working with test cases in your, project, in those cases, you can pass those unit tests also. So right now.
PAUL: Some unit test cases, if you have, so simply, you can skip this part initially. Later on, you can add test cases also. Okay, so first of all, to set up the CI part. In the CI part, it means that I'll be taking,
PAUL: an environment. In that environment, I'll be doing the setup, I'll be installing all the requirements. Okay, and then if I want, I can run my test cases. So, if you remember in the last class, there were two requirements fine. Okay, but right now, it's single. So, generally, for your test cases run, it's a good practice to check your entire dev environment.
PAUL: So, in the requirements dev.txt file, you'll be having packages like, rough.
PAUL: Black, or any other linters or formatters that you are using.
PAUL: Now, these two are the main things that needs to be focused on right now, which is the Docker build job. Check out the code, build…
PAUL: the Docker build, okay, you will be getting the exact information of your image once it's done, the layers will be captured, and then the Docker image will be running in that particular environment.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the first step in the CI.
PAUL: Always remember, so we have done the automation where automatically the Docker build will take place in your CI integrations.
PAUL: Is this pipeline will be the same? No, this pipeline can be different. It's not necessary, but this job, this task will be pretty much same. Now, in some projects, I might not use unit tests. Here also, like, currently that we'll be doing, there are no unit tests.
PAUL: But if you are working with test cases, which is pretty much common in those cases that you can prepare all your test cases in one shot, and you can run them so that everything gets checked.
PAUL: Okay, so the first of all, the same thing that we have done it in local. We have to do the testing that, okay, in our environment, during our continuous integration checks, everything is working fine or not.
PAUL: Yes, I'll be sharing the workflow, don't worry.
PAUL: Okay, now, a few security scan checks using few packages like Bandit and SEPTI, which you can run, but again, these are optional checks.
PAUL: Now, if the pipeline is success, the branch is main, because in our case, I hope everybody's working on the main branch.
PAUL: If anything that fails, simply we will be getting the pipeline as failed. Okay, so the file that we'll be creating, right now, the deploy.yml file, which will trigger your CD part, the continuous deployment part.
PAUL: Okay, so let's start with the, first of all, the continuous integration part, first of all, and then we will jump into the CD part.
PAUL: Alright, so let me share the script.
PAUL: Yes, after the class, I will add it in motion, don't worry.
PAUL: So, let me just get the flow… I think… okay.
PAUL: I have to… first of all, let me just create a folder.
PAUL: Where is my anti-gravity? Alright, yes.
PAUL: So here, I'll be creating a folder now, in this part.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just create a folder. I'll be giving the name .github slash workflows.
PAUL: Okay, everybody, please create that .github slash workflows.
PAUL: Here, I'll be creating a new file.
PAUL: Which is CI.YM.
PAUL: Everybody, please do create, and then I'll be pushing it, so don't worry.
PAUL: So everybody, please create the folder within that CI.YME.
PAUL: Please?
PAUL: Let me know once you have done it.
PAUL: It's just creating the simple folder, and within that, CI.YML.
PAUL: Now, I'll be bringing, bringing the contents of CI.YML, so let me get it.
PAUL: Okay, I will do, and I will push it. Don't worry, I will do a push, and then we will start our discussion exactly what is there in this file.
PAUL: Now, before the push, Everybody please open your GitHub repo.
PAUL: the actual GitHub repo that you have been using.
PAUL: Everyone.
PAUL: Okay, so this is my GitHub repo. Inside the GitHub repo, I have to pass a few environment variables. Okay, so just click on Settings. So, in the repo, on the top section, you will be getting the settings part.
PAUL: From Settings, click on Secrets and Variables.
PAUL: Okay, so from Secrets and variables, you have to click on Actions.
PAUL: Everybody please follow. You have to do this, then I will be talking about the CI part. Because, first of all, in the CI files, there are certain environment variables, so you need to pass those environment variables.
PAUL: Okay, and these are the set of environment variables that you need to pass it.
PAUL: Okay, so all these, I'm… just…
PAUL: Keeping it in one place so that it becomes easier.
PAUL: Nothing where is Notion.
PAUL: ENV variables for GitHub Actions.
PAUL: The first one?
PAUL: is AppRunner?
PAUL: ECR Access Rule ARM.
PAUL: Then the next one, KWS Access Key, you already have it in your CSV files with you?
PAUL: Then comes AR Enroll, I'll be talking about that, don't worry how you can get it. AWS Secret Access Key.
PAUL: This, also, you have it in your CSV file.
PAUL: Landsmith API key, this also you have in your .env file.
PAUL: Then comes your OpenAI API key.
PAUL: So, all the list of environment variables
PAUL: We'll be passing it in our GitHub secrets. Then comes your quadrant, He… Okay, and the quadrant URL.
PAUL: Okay? Now, these are the environment variables that you need to pass. So, what you have to do? You have to go here, you have to click on this green color button, which is Retania's New Repo Secret. Okay.
PAUL: Click on this.
PAUL: Pazdani.
PAUL: Okay, so pass the name, for example, AWS Access Key, and paste the value. You guys already know the value. I think everybody of you knows the value, because it is available in your CSV file that you have downloaded when you created the access key. Okay, so please paste all these values and just be ready.
PAUL: Everyone. It will take some time. Please do the configuration correctly, and please do the verification. If something, like, if you add even an extra white space, it can be an issue. So just be sure you are passing everything correctly.
PAUL: Okay, now coming to this app runner ECR access rule.
PAUL: Okay, now, how to get this, particular other environment variable you can configure, leave this AWS, I'll be telling you how to get this information.
PAUL: Everyone, please do the configuration.
PAUL: From, click on Settings.
PAUL: After Settings, please click on Actions. Once you have clicked on Actions, you can see here.
PAUL: So, secrets by default, so click on this green color button, the new repository secret.
PAUL: and all the things that I have added it here, one by one. I've added the keys.
PAUL: Okay, now you have to just paste the values, so please update the portal. There are six
PAUL: environment variables, or Ripple secrets.
PAUL: variable limo already pasted in Notion. Please check.
PAUL: Yes, just be sure you are logged into your GitHub account, that is the bare minimum.
PAUL: Perfect.
PAUL: I have shared the command also, how you'll be getting your…
PAUL: runner ECR access rule, ARM, you have to copy this command, and you have to paste it in your terminal. So, for example, if I'm here.
PAUL: Alright, so let me just pass it.
PAUL: Okay, and you will be getting the information. So this exact information, you have to copy-paste it there.
PAUL: in your, values, because already the key I have shared, just be sure you are passing the correct one. Don't use mine.
PAUL: Okay, I'm just showing you the format. It will look something like this. Again, I am repeating.
PAUL: The output that you'll be getting from the command, you need to paste it in your,
PAUL: like, secret one for app runner ECR Access Role AR.
PAUL: Somebody's telling me we are not getting this view in GitHub. By default, this is the view. If you have any repo in your account, always there will be settings. Click on settings, then click on
PAUL: Secrets and variables, and from your actions. Done.
PAUL: I think you guys have your own repo, no? Please let me know.
PAUL: Are you guys pushing the code, like, whenever you are doing it? If you have not pushed it, then just create a repo and push your code.
PAUL: Otherwise, simply clone. As simple as that. Simply do a clone of it.
PAUL: Guys, see, at every point of time, the idea is that you guys push the code.
PAUL: Add… three commands are there, git, add, dot.
PAUL: Okay, and then git commit hyphen M, add your GitHub message, and then do a git push hyphen U, and whichever branch, from origin to your main branch for now.
PAUL: Okay, please take your time, I'm giving you 5 minutes, do the setup.
PAUL: And set up the environment variables.
PAUL: That is the command from where you can get the rule. Otherwise, when you created the repo, I think, at that particular point of time also, you will be getting the information with the ARN.
PAUL: So, using this command, you can easily get your, rule. Otherwise, if…
PAUL: For ARN, if you want it, you can do the other way. I think, where is my AWS account?
PAUL: I think, this one, I created it.
PAUL: the repo URN, this information from here also, you can get it.
PAUL: So, I've already given you the command, do it through command. I prefer it much more, because that ESR access rule is provided.
PAUL: Everybody?
PAUL: Please let me know. First of all, the cloning part is done for the repo.
PAUL: Or the code that you have in your local machine for that, you have pushed it to GitHub.
PAUL: That is the first step. Once you have pushed it for your repo, you'll be getting the settings option.
PAUL: From Settings, You have to click on.
PAUL: Now, where is… no, not this one. Yes. You have to click on Settings, and you have to go to Actions.
PAUL: From secret and variables, you'll be getting the action, actions option, and then you have to pass your secrets, one by one.
PAUL: Not able to get the command, the command is there in Notion, I think.
PAUL: Yes, I have shared the command in motion.
PAUL: Using the command, please get the access role, KRN.
PAUL: It's the same notion that we have been using from day one, Vipen. There are no changes in Notion.
PAUL: Here, you will be getting that app runner EASR access role, that's why I've shared you the command.
PAUL: Here, you'll be getting just the repo URL, but the ESR, that's why, using the command, please do create that.
PAUL: I think, alright. You have till now not created, that is also correct, I think, Murta, I say. Because the app runner ECR access rule
PAUL: Till now, you have not done it. Alright, fine. At mean time, just leave this part, configure the other repos for now.
PAUL: Okay, leave this variable, please do the configuration for others at least.
PAUL: Yes, fine, fine, fine, leave that part. Please do the configuration at least for the others.
PAUL: The repo URL is there in GitHub. Please do have a check. So, here I've shared.
PAUL: This is the repo that I'm using for now.
PAUL: Rishi… Rishi, fine, fine, leave that part, leave that part.
PAUL: have planar, but we have not configured yet.
PAUL: Okay, leave that part, but at least the other, all these things, 5.
PAUL: Please be sure you have done that.
PAUL: Everybody, once you have done it, please let me know in the chat.
PAUL: The first part is done.
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Cloning the repo, setting up the environment values, at least.
PAUL: Totals 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 6 values are there.
PAUL: leave the part with the app runner ECR access rule, but please do the configuration for the others at least.
PAUL: Yes, all the secret value has to be without double quotes.
PAUL: Just paste the original value, don't add anything from your end.
PAUL: Okay, alright, Millin, do it, fine.
PAUL: And when you are… whenever you are pushing your code, please don't push the .env file.
PAUL: Please use .gitignore always.
PAUL: Alright, people are telling, doing, alright, doing, doing, doing, everybody's doing state.
PAUL: Okay, a few people are done, let's wait for others.
PAUL: Alright, leave that part.
PAUL: Okay, now coming to the CI file, I have…
PAUL: I'm pushing the file right now.
PAUL: Okay, so even I have pushed the CI file, so I think everybody has created the folder, so let's get the content.
PAUL: Mmm, I think in the shippo…
PAUL: Yeah, so let's go to project class…
PAUL: Okay, here you can see, this got added. Please go inside this, and you'll be getting your CI.YML file.
PAUL: Please get the content of the CI.YML file, I have pushed it.
PAUL: Everybody.
PAUL: Alright, Amit, you can do the configuration later on. If any issues, let me know tomorrow.
PAUL: I think everybody has access to the CII.YML file that I have pushed right now.
PAUL: Yeah.
PAUL: And one thing that I will do here.
PAUL: Okay, so we'll leave this, make it main…
PAUL: Okay, so here, also mean, I will make it.
PAUL: Meaning… Docker main. Okay, so, alright, let me just, parl that updated one.
PAUL: Right, no, Only the branch name, just be sure.
PAUL: You have changed it.
PAUL: Please copy the content of the ci.yml file, and please pass it.
PAUL: Okay, create the file.
PAUL: For how many of you the file is created. And just be sure, because we are working on the main branch, you have the main branch as the selected one.
PAUL: Where we can get the CI.YML file in the same repo that we were discussing.
PAUL: The repo is exactly the same, no?
PAUL: Today's report is that RAC project for Alzakati Nation.
PAUL: You forked my repo, but be sure, like,
PAUL: Because, see, again, I have pushed something, so…
PAUL: just do a git pull and just be updated.
PAUL: So just be sure, inside your fork, okay, the branch is correct.
PAUL: It has to be me. Please don't use features. Everybody, please do the sync. So right now, if you really look into here, I think.
PAUL: Some, the CI pipeline has started.
PAUL: Building the Docker image.
PAUL: Alright, yes, it is going on right now.
PAUL: The continuous integration phase has started.
PAUL: Okay, it will go on.
PAUL: is just push. Just push.
PAUL: Only push is required, nothing else.
PAUL: You can always go to Actions, and you can click there.
PAUL: There is no command to run the build. You have to just do a commit operation.
PAUL: The page is taking too long to load, alright, fine, let's get back.
PAUL: Okay, you will see one yellow color option here. If it works good, then it will become a green color, otherwise the red color cross that you can see.
PAUL: Okay, good.
PAUL: shared the Notion link.
PAUL: In actions, you have to just vault the environment variable, Samit Kumar, nothing else.
PAUL: Everybody, please check, once you have done the commit, whether it has started, because, again, if I pass anything here.
PAUL: So again, automatically the commit will start. Okay, so right now the build is going on. Once the build is done, the CI part, then I will test it out again by making another commit for now.
PAUL: Okay, so let me check the status.
PAUL: I'll still drag over here.
PAUL: I think rag project class… the build is still now going on. Alright, fine. Let me check the details here.
PAUL: In actions, first time, it's asking.
PAUL: In action, first time it's asking me.
PAUL: No, no, CI.ML. Generally, the term main.yml is also used. I'm using the ILMCI. Otherwise, main is also used a lot.
PAUL: It's just a naming convention that can be used.
PAUL: Alright, so the app loaded successfully, post-build Docker image, post job cleanup, removing, post-catcher, alright. This part is done. Okay, I think Docker build…
PAUL: The first part.
PAUL: This is not a meeting, Abhiji, this is a webinar.
PAUL: Alright, let's get back here.
PAUL: Yes, I will come to CI first.
PAUL: P.
PAUL: Whether it's working or not, then I will come to what I exactly have passed in CI.YML file.
PAUL: Because in your case, at least this process should start. Okay? So, fine, it's going in my system, in somebody's system who has already done
PAUL: Yes, do the modification, just check the name of the branch, Melind. That's the only thing. And right now, keys are not required. Anyone, like, if you want to
PAUL: share your screen, I can take on volunteer, and let's say in your system what exactly is going. And just be sure everything you have in your system. Till now, whatever I have discussed, you have the CI.YML file, everything. So, simply, you can raise your hand. Based on that, I can take you, and I can ask you to do the screen sharing.
PAUL: Okay, how many of your CI.YML file is already?
PAUL: Configured everything? Okay, Pramesh, alright. Pramesh will add in.
PAUL: Okay, Pramish, please start sharing.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Yeah, I'll share my screen.
PAUL: Okay, so…
PAUL: Again, we will repeat the step. No, we are not done. CI, I have not discussed. CT is remaining. Things are remaining, don't worry.
PAUL: Alright, so this is your, GitHub. 6 minutes ago, you have pushed. Alright,
PAUL: Go back to your VS Code, like, wherever you are keeping the scripts. Open the idea.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Let me share my… reshare my whole screen.
PAUL: Yes, yes, please do that.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Yeah.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Yes.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Here it is.
PAUL: Okay, first of all, go to that, ci.yml file.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: That is all… I already posted in GitHub, I can show you there. It is there.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: I directly posted… I pasted it here.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: In this…
PAUL: No, no, no, see, then make a sync with the report. Don't do in this way, always.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: I don't prefer directly pasting. Get this file in your local machine.
PAUL: Then I will make the… Commit. That's the main thing.
PAUL: And here, in the branches, directly, the features part, please keep it main.
PAUL: branches.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Yep.
PAUL: Do the changes? Yes.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Okay, let'.
PAUL: Can't I push to my FB? What is FB you are referring?
PAUL: Yes, Deepak, what is MB?
PAUL: Alrighty, if you have a feature branch, you can do that.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: If you have a feature branch, you can do that.
PAUL: But right now, majorly, the task that we'll be doing, it is in our main branch.
PAUL: If you are good with Git, you can do it in any branch, but, like, for beginners, let's try to stick to the main one.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Yep.
PAUL: Okay, now, line number, 9 and 11, change that feature to me.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: this main…
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes, change that to me.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: make…
PAUL: Main, M-A-I-N, the main branch.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Similarly, line number 11.
PAUL: Okay? Do a Ctrl-F.
PAUL: And, okay, previously the pool was there. If you try to push it, push it to get up.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Okay.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: I have done that push.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no, no, no. First do, git add the file that you have added.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: And…
PAUL: Always do get pool first.
PAUL: Pay in sync. Otherwise, again, you will be…
PAUL: Stuck in this particular loop only.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Okay.
PAUL: Now check the file once again if something got updated.
PAUL: Because in there, it was not updated.
PAUL: So just be sure, this is the modified version of the pool, okay, now try to make a commit.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Direct push.
PAUL: Getting yellow color now, Amit, alright. How many of you are getting the yellow color after the… who shall be getting that?
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Good comment.
PAUL: You are also new to Git, looks like.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Yes, yes, yes.
PAUL: then do it from VS Code while you are doing it from the terminal. In VS Code, you have all the features.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: I'm using cursor, so here…
PAUL: Does it matter whether you are on a VS Code, everybody has the VCS systems integrated in their ID.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Okay.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: I can, for now, for the time being, should I modify here directly?
PAUL: Just do one thing directly from here, do the change.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Yes.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Yeah.
PAUL: economic changes.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Yes.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Done.
PAUL: Okay, now go back to your main, repo page.
PAUL: project, this one, rack project class, okay, you can see the yellow color game.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Yeah.
PAUL: Click on the yellow color.
PAUL: Okay, so the build is going.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Similarly, for others, also, you can see the build is going.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Okay.
PAUL: Okay. Alright.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Thank you so much.
PRAMESH ANURAGI: Yes.
PAUL: Alright, this part is done, we have taken.
PAUL: Rajat, okay, Rajat, I can take you.
PAUL: Rajat already, you can share your screen.
PAUL: How to create CI.YML file? Go to VS Code, there is option of creating files, click on that, and create it, done.
Rajat Khanna: My screen is visible, Paul.
PAUL: Yes.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so, I might be one step behind, like, I have created a new repo, just copy-pasted it, and pushed into my own branch, so you can see it's my branch and drag QA, and I'm, a step behind for this very.
PAUL: Leave the secrets, leave the secrets part, just, right now I'm working on the CI part, show me that one.
Rajat Khanna: So, I have not, pasted that CI file right now, so…
PAUL: do that.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: We will be discussing the project, don't worry. Few people are getting stuck, so the idea is that to show the same process at least two to three times, so that everybody can follow.
PAUL: Create the repo, push it, Then add the CI.YML file, again push it, automatically the build will start.
PAUL: That's the purpose of using CR, for your continuous integration with GitHub Actions.
Rajat Khanna: Oh, no!
PAUL: Alright, now go to the main repo page.
Rajat Khanna: There are tight.
Rajat Khanna: Quite surprising urge to find the food.
Rajat Khanna: Simple.
PAUL: It has to be .github slash workflows.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: dot github slash.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, cool.
PAUL: Using data of actions, you can perform CICT operations upon the sunny.
PAUL: There are so many CI, tools out there. Anybody have used CircleCI?
PAUL: Because, really, so many CI2s are Travis CI,
PAUL: So, similarly, like, using GitHub Actions, you can perform the same thing with respect to your CI CD bit.
PAUL: And it's much easier, actually, than making other configurations, so I picked up with GitHub Actions.
PAUL: Atlantis, okay, on the town.
PAUL: ML guys uses CI a lot, but in CI.
PAUL: Alright, now build has started. Similarly, like, everybody will see the build…
Rajat Khanna: We'll start.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, so Saurabh, what's the point of adding all those, variables?
PAUL: That will come in CB.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, yeah, thank you, Anim.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the part with…
PAUL: Alright, so, even for him, it's working. Anybody who…
PAUL: For whom it is not working.
PAUL: The build has not started.
PAUL: Yes, you can take a fork off the repo, there is no issue, Deepak.
PAUL: Okay, you're gonna take a fork. Yes, please let me know.
PAUL: For how many of you the build started, and it's going on. It will take some time.
PAUL: If I, show you my screen, in my case also, you can see… let me just do a reload this browser, actually.
PAUL: Okay, you can see this green color will come with a success.
PAUL: Okay, it's completed for you, alright.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Right. Alright, like, few have taken the question, but I hope that for most of you, it should work. Because first, CI will come into the picture, then only CD will come.
PAUL: I will do it on weekdays, Rachute.
PAUL: Alright, so the first part is done. Now, let's talk about the contents of the CI file that I have.
PAUL: So, first of all, here, just focus on the file.
PAUL: So, name, I am passing as CI pipeline. On push, like, whenever I make a push, or basically I make a commit to this particular branch, it will be detected, and the trigger will take place. So, first of all, here I'm doing a Docker build test.
PAUL: Okay, and run on which system? So, the Ubuntu latest image, already GitHub Actions, it has. On top of that, the build will take place. Okay, so few steps, like checking out the code, setting up your Docker buildex, so these are simple commands that you have to remember for GitHub Actions.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Setting up the Docker build, looking into your final image. Okay, and these are a few tags that I have passed. RAT eval system, for now, the name of the image that I want. You can change anything. This part can be changed by you.
PAUL: Now, here, one thing, like, going forward in this particular fashion. Now, this fashion is referred to as, like, whenever you look into github.shhi, sometimes I can pass environment variables also, here.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, this is the Docker image tag that I have passed.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, you can see these are simple commands through which you'll be running.
PAUL: the Docker file.
PAUL: And on top of that, if you want, you can perform some type of health check also. So right now, first, the build is done. Once the build is done, then, in the next step, you can…
PAUL: actually run your application. And you can see here, from app, main, okay, the app is successfully loaded.
PAUL: Now, this is, the information that you'll be getting.
PAUL: here also. So, in our final… Shiite part.
PAUL: post-build Docker image.
PAUL: Alright, docker buildX… Okay, the Git version, cleaning, pretty much job completed.
PAUL: Alright, orphan process is also killed.
PAUL: So, majorly with respect to the build, first, then, running your application.
PAUL: everything step-by-step, it worked good. And if your Docker is not working, it means that if there is some issue with the image here only it will fail.
PAUL: Okay, always remember that. And from this app loaded successfully, I know that my application is running successfully, within the Ubuntu environment, which GitHub Access is providing.
PAUL: For how many of you the build is successful, please let me know.
PAUL: Yes, for how many of you the build is successful.
PAUL: Yes, successful, successful, alright. Many of you are telling, it's successful.
PAUL: Alright, fine. So, the CI part is done. Now we will come to the part with…
PAUL: CD. Now, CD part, really, like, I will be…
PAUL: Providing you the script for CD?
PAUL: So, let's take the CD part once more.
PAUL: I think let me get my…
PAUL: Okay, CI file is updated, let me just change…
PAUL: my branch, I have the deploy.yml file here.
PAUL: Okay, now this file, I'll be…
PAUL: keeping it in my local machine. So, another file that I'll be creating here, CI is here. I will create a file, deploy.biam.
PAUL: dot Wyomi.
PAUL: And here, I'll be passing the information with respect to deployment.
PAUL: Everyone?
PAUL: I'm… I will be making the commit, don't worry. Pick up my commit, it will be better.
PAUL: Stinky…
PAUL: Great.
PAUL: Alright, so I've pushed the file deploy.vml.
PAUL: Please do.
PAUL: Check.
PAUL: I think in your repo now,
PAUL: If I go to the main branch… Yes, deploy is there.
PAUL: Okay, so check… okay. Now, in this file, the major update that you have to do, first of all, you have to check the features. So, please go to the repo.
PAUL: Okay, you will be getting the deploy.yml file. In that deploy.yml file, you have to change this features part.
PAUL: Just be sure you have changed the features one.
PAUL: Okay, so these features will become main. So, let me just push this change.
PAUL: branch updated.
PAUL: I don't think any other place that I need to make the update.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Alright, so I have updated the branch also in GitHub.
PAUL: I will come to the explanation. First of all, get the file.
PAUL: And just be sure the contents in your file are synced.
PAUL: Yes, you can commit again and again, there is no issue with comments.
PAUL: Whenever you make a commit, automatically the CI process will start, every time.
PAUL: Is this part clear for everyone?
PAUL: Okay, if you are looking into uploaded successfully, it means that it is working fine.
PAUL: Because for this build, even, I might get errors, okay?
PAUL: Alright, because I have changed this script as compared to the previous one in the RAT project Q&A. That script is different, and this is different.
PAUL: All right. Now, here, the first thing in this content of the file. Okay, the name is CD deploy to AWS on push, on which branch? Main. Workflow dispatch, so here I can make a manual trigger also, because of that, within the actions, you do have a workflow dispatch option.
PAUL: Now, setting up a few important things from the environment perspective, like AWS region, US East One. What is the name of the ECR report that you have passed? Okay, I think the name of the report in my case, it was different.
PAUL: Okay, I don't remember, just wait, I have to look into.
PAUL: Somewhere from here, I will get it. Okay, rack Q event, system hyphen hybrid.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just pass the correct name.
PAUL: hyphen hybrid. Okay, this is the name that I have given.
PAUL: Age single, yes.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Okay, okay, okay, okay.
PAUL: I have pasted in here, actually.
PAUL: Let me make a tag for now.
PAUL: Alright, so two things that I have done. So, here I'm passing exactly what will be the app runner service name, and what is the ECR repo. You guys have already created the repo, so you guys know the name exactly, so just be sure you are passing the correct name.
PAUL: So, the first stage here is to push.
PAUL: So anything, like, to build the image and to push it. So that's why the first stage
PAUL: So, during your deployment, we are telling that, okay, there are jobs. Now, there are two main jobs. The first job is to build the image and push it to ICR. This is the first step. Once the image is pushed, then you can actually do the deployment with AppRun.
PAUL: Okay, so two steps are there. So, let's focus on the first one. So, for the build and push, okay, now this will be executing on the Ubuntu latest.
PAUL: output, now it will be showing you the output, like, you will be getting the image URI.
PAUL: Okay, now this will be detected through your environment variables also. And now.
PAUL: The steps are very similar steps, like accent checkout, AWS actions with configure AWS credentials V4, okay? And where you will be passing your AWS credentials? In your secrets, in your GitHub secrets. From there, it will pick it up. Now, can you see that these three things are there?
PAUL: and AWS underscore region, I think by default, I have passed it as US-East 1. Okay, so automatically it will be picked up, but sometimes we keep this AWS region inside your environment variable also. I feel that is a better practice, but right now, I know that, for initial purpose.
PAUL: This is fine. So all this… these three settings will be picked up from the secrets of GitHub.
PAUL: Now, the next step is to log into your ECR service. It means that to start the build process and finally push it, so you need to log into your Amazon ECR service.
PAUL: Once the login is successful, the next step is basically to build, tag, and push the image to GCR. So the ECR image registry, you already have this information, the image tag. So, generally, you can use the tag latest, or some other mechanism, there is no problem with that.
PAUL: Now, the commands…
PAUL: to be executed, like, docker build hyphen T, this is the ECR registry, so that's, first of all, the registry comes, and the repo comes, and this is the image stack. Now, this is a universal format. It means that
PAUL: where you are working with any artifact registry, everywhere, whether it is JCP, AWS, or Azure.
PAUL: Okay, so…
PAUL: Two build commands that I have kept it, generally, a single build command is also fine. If you have for the tags, otherwise, right now, I will be using the latest tag, the second command.
PAUL: Now, as you can see, push both the tags, so if you want to keep the latest, as well as any current image tagging that you are following on it. Okay, so most of the times, I can say that I can comment out the first line. Okay, you can comment this line and this line. Later on, we can test it out.
PAUL: Okay, but initially, one build command is important.
PAUL: and one push command. You can upload multiple images also.
PAUL: Okay, the same version with a different tag.
PAUL: Now, finally, you'll be getting the image URI once the image is finally pushed there, so that's why I've kept an eco command, just to show you some print statements during that particular build through GitHub Actions. Now, once the image is pushed, what is the idea? To use this apprunner.
PAUL: For our deployment. We know that, okay, from the ECR, whichever latest image is available, okay, we will pull that image, and we'll be deploying it in AppRana.
PAUL: So, first of all, the name, deployed to AppRunner, runs on Ubuntu letters, needs build and push, steps, very similar steps, just like last time that we have done. If you really look into this part, remains the same.
PAUL: Now, check if the app runner service exists or not. So, first of all, we'll be having a check, and here, we'll be looking into, like, AWS region and app runner service, two things. If the service is not available, it will be created. Okay, so sometimes what happens, like, if the
PAUL: If it is already running, then you might get an error. The service already exists, so nothing that you can do from your end. Okay, so first of all, I'm doing a check that if the service exists or not, if it is…
PAUL: If it exists, okay, then we know that we have to update the service. If it doesn't exist, then you'll be creating a new service, okay? So that's why this name, CreateAppRunner Service, if it doesn't exist.
PAUL: And right now, you can see I'm using simple AWS app runner create service. Service name, region, configuration. So, in this way, through these commands also, you can do it.
PAUL: So, previously, I was using the environments, and I was getting an error. So, directly, I've taken the AWS command from here. Through that command, you can see that I am passing all my environment variables.
PAUL: So, I think only one environment variable, which is remaining that we need to take care of. Other than that, everything, we have done it.
PAUL: Alright, then finally, doing an authentication, configuration. So, here, this app runner ECR access rule, ERN, that is defined. So, auto-deployment enabled, you can make it true. Then I'm telling, for the deployment, in AppRunner, what will be the configuration?
PAUL: You can change those numbers. Like, you can make it 3GB, you can make it 4GB, okay? So, 1V CPU with a memory of 2GB, I know that it is fine. Then comes our health check configuration. For that, I'm using that slash health route.
PAUL: Okay, interval 10 and, like, timeout 5 that I have given.
PAUL: Then we are printing out the information with respect to service ARN and URL. So you can see that I'm doing an echoing operation. ECO is just like a printout, print statement that I have added. Once the service is created.
PAUL: Okay. Now, update the app runner service if this exists. So, first of all, check whether it exists or not. If it doesn't exist, then create one, and the other one is basically to update. So, 3 things that I have.
PAUL: Now, wait for the service to be ready. So, here, this is… there is a timeout check where, like, every 10 seconds we do a poll, and we look for the service is ready or not. Okay, so waiting for the service to be ready, it generally takes
PAUL: 2 to 3 minutes, so you have to, wait. So that's why this full service status, if it's running. So everything will be printed with print statements. So for that, I have kept this particular script.
PAUL: Alright, now, while attempting, so here, a few conditions that I've kept for this status variable. This status variable will actually tell you that your app runner is up or not, so that's why if status is equal to running, then the service is running and ready. Okay, it's just a check.
PAUL: I thought about keeping more eco-statements in the CI. in the deploy.yml file, which becomes easier at any point of time to get it. Now, once the app runner service is available, it means that it will show you the status as successful. Okay, otherwise, simply, it will throw you the service deployment failed with some type of errors.
PAUL: It can be with respect to build, or some other issue.
PAUL: Now, the next thing, getting the service URL. Okay, now, once the deployment is successful, you will be getting the URL for the AppRunner application directly. It means that you will be… you will be clicking on that URL, and the application will be available.
PAUL: Okay, so get the service URL, and then finally printing out your apprunner URL in this step.
PAUL: So, two things. So, here also you can see the service, service, service. So, everywhere we are getting the main information. So, create, update, if there is a service which is existing, you'll be looking for it.
PAUL: And once the service is up, the final check is the health check, whether the URL that is hosted, whether it's working or not. Okay, so there also, I'm calling the slash health route, which will help me to tell that, yes, the application is working fine. And finally printing out, yes, the health check.
PAUL: Passing, or, like, pend operation.
PAUL: So, using call directly, I am enabling it. So, this is the part with the deployment part.
PAUL: It's your choice, see, you can do a build here also. Okay, here I have kept the build again. Otherwise, it's not necessary. Like, after CI also, you can do a build. Totally up to you, because these configurations are totally customized, depends upon one preference. I'm just showing you one of the simplest version.
PAUL: AppRunner is like Kubernetes, no, it's not Kubernetes.
PAUL: Alright, two different commits can run in action, not a problem.
PAUL: Okay, now the first part comes, like, creating the rule. I have to create the rule.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Let me just get back to…
PAUL: Alright, fine, here, I think some… that build part is going on, not an issue.
PAUL: Alright, so here you can see, like, in my case, I think I have done something, and there I was getting some error.
PAUL: Okay, and… really, like, I have not updated anything, okay, and my configuration. So you can see during the build and the push, it's telling that, okay, the repo with the name key, rack UIDS system doesn't exist. We know that the repo name is different in our case, okay?
PAUL: So right now, I will do a final check. RACU and the system, this is the name.
PAUL: Alright, the AppRunner, service… Hi, Planner!
PAUL: I can create it from here also, because in the problem with AppRunner that I always
PAUL: Fill the auto-configuration settings.
PAUL: Okay, now, let's…
PAUL: Because you have to pass the environment variables in your app run. Okay, I've already shared in the
PAUL: deployment part, but what happens? For your initial, in one shot, it doesn't take place, the update. So, for example, if I show you my app runner command, can you see here?
PAUL: the ad…
PAUL: create service. Now, here I am actually passing in everything. But generally, for the first instance, when it runs, everything doesn't get detected. So that's why this update operation, that we do it sometimes.
PAUL: Who… let me take the build part first of all.
PAUL: And you need the access rule, I think.
PAUL: Browse, choose Repo. I think this is the name that I have given, Rack US System Hybrid.
PAUL: Fuck… Right now, there are no images here.
PAUL: Alright, this will be picked up from their provider, alright.
PAUL: So, automatic trigger, ECR… Imagiwa, right?
PAUL: Create a new service.
PAUL: Because I have not done the push there upon…
PAUL: Actually, during your CI part, you can make sure that the image is uploaded also.
PAUL: Because I think if I go to my ECR, there will be at least one image. Let me see…
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Let me just wait to read it.
PAUL: ECR…
PAUL: Alright, so the rack, Q&A system hybrid.
PAUL: This is the name. So let's start with the first part of the build, and let's see at least am I getting the image or not. Step by step, we will debug it, and then I will come to the part with respect to the access rule.
PAUL: Okay, so the reactive and the system hybrid, and this is the name of the app, alright?
PAUL: So, I think deploy… CD update, fine.
PAUL: Commit, let me start with the update part.
PAUL: Now, my build should start. Let me open my build.
PAUL: Not great.
PAUL: Let's see.
PAUL: Because the first part, is to build and push to ECR. So let's say at least the first step is working or not.
PAUL: In this particular commit, okay. Two steps will be going on if you really look into the first phase, the CI phase, and then we come to the CD phase.
PAUL: That is the name of the service.
PAUL: You can give any name to the service.
PAUL: Okay, the first phase is done, now it will move to the CD phase, let's see.
PAUL: I note that the app runner part, it will throw me an error.
PAUL: But, at least for the other
PAUL: Now, let's see, logging to ECR is done. Image is pushed, can you see? This is the field, actually, I was looking for.
PAUL: Can you see here Because the deployment,
PAUL: Two is here, that will fail. Leave that.
PAUL: this part should work, because once you have configured this, I know that, okay, the build and push is working fine.
PAUL: So here, if I try to reload this page, I'll be getting some image here. Can you see the image has been automatically pushed?
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Please let me know how many of you are getting that the image is available through the push.
PAUL: Yes, Hardik, you can do it anyway. There is no restriction in that.
PAUL: Alright, so this is the first part.
PAUL: We'll write the… build and push to ECR is done.
PAUL: Great. Now, see, the next step, once the pusher, then comes your app runner part. So, generally, like,
PAUL: Right now, for me, the service has already started. It takes some time, just wait, don't worry, I will just check whether it's working or not. In my case, if it fails, then I will come to that.
PAUL: Now, the question comes, if the image is available. Now, using this image, I'll be doing the deployment, okay? So, if I go to AppRunner, let's go and let me just click on create a service. From here, Container Registry, Amazon ECR Private Repo. Let's go to the repo, for example, QS System Hybrid.
PAUL: Okay, and the image tag… That I am choosing is lettuce.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Let's go… continue.
PAUL: Now, the question comes, automatic-based triggers that you want, automatic. Now, this is the ECR access role within the AR. So, let me just click on create a new role, app runner ECR Access Rule. This is the actual rule, because till now, this rule will be missing, I think, in your case.
PAUL: Now, let me do the next…
PAUL: Okay, now this is the name of the service, so the configuration. Here, I'm passing the app runner service name, so this name that I have.
PAUL: So, let me just give a different name this time. I will just pick up.
PAUL: a test one that I'm doing right now. Virtual CPU one, virtual this one. Now, can you see here you have to pass all the environment variables one by one?
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: these environment variables. Now, these environment variables you can pick up from your secret manager, or you can keep them as plain text.
PAUL: Then comes the port.
PAUL: exactly which… in which port the application will be running. By default, sir, it… it is AT80.
PAUL: Then comes some check with respect to auto-scaling.
PAUL: Okay, health check, security, and these are the default settings, you don't need to change anything here.
PAUL: Now, if you just try to go and click on Next.
PAUL: You will see that automatically, it will do a review complete, and can you see here, you will be getting the ECR access rule.
PAUL: From here, also, you can get this rule. This is the actual information that you need to pass it in your GitHub secrets.
PAUL: Right now, I'm not past any environment variables, so let's leave this part.
PAUL: Let me look into my logs, waiting for the service to be ready.
PAUL: It's taking some time, so let's wait.
PAUL: In the meantime, what you guys can do, simply create a service.
PAUL: Okay, if… how… tell me the first part is working for how many of you? Like, the first part, which is pushing the image to ECR.
PAUL: For how many of you, that part is done? Because that is 50% of the work. The next 50% is the Aprana.
PAUL: The first part working?
PAUL: It means that check your ECR, it means that the image is available or not.
PAUL: Please check.
PAUL: Is the first part done?
PAUL: Image push to ECR, fine, how do we do that?
PAUL: There is no way to do, by default, when your CD gets, initialized through your commit, automatically, that trigger will make the push to the repo, Milith.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: If you do the commit, automatically the image build will take place, and then it will be pushed to ECR. For how many of you, the image has been pushed to ECR. This is the first step.
PAUL: I'm not talking about app run or anything, only the first stage, the ECR part. Is it done? Image pushed?
PAUL: I have no idea if your commit is getting blocked or anything like that.
PAUL: No, see, in the CD part, there are two things. First of all, let me just show you two tasks which are there.
PAUL: Okay, so here I think the deployment is done, or what?
PAUL: Yes, the deployment to AppRunner is done.
PAUL: I think, this is the service URL app.
PAUL: Okay, I'm just checking that the application is working or not.
PAUL: Looks like, the deployment is successful in my case. Don't worry, I will come to you. I will just check the routes also.
PAUL: dos… slash… And docs… Alright, the swagger part is working fine. Let me just take a query for now.
PAUL: Alright, so I know the application is often working in my case. Okay, there are no major changes. So, the first part is working with the ECR repo part.
PAUL: If the ECR repo is working, and you can actually see the service, what you can do.
PAUL: create a new service based on the new name. Okay, for safety only, I'm telling.
PAUL: Now, just create the repo.
PAUL: Okay, and okay, this is the ECR part I was talking about, the app runner part, yes.
PAUL: Create a new service.
PAUL: Pass your ECR image repo, okay, do an automatic
PAUL: Okay, or manual for now, there is no issue with that. The idea is, please get the access rule. What I will do, see, I will just create with the same name, whatever the name was available.
PAUL: QA App Hybrid. This is the name.
PAUL: Okay, already I have the service with me, so let me just click on next. Just check the settings, I am selecting repo type, provider. Right now, we know these are private repos that I have. Then comes the image.
PAUL: Select the repo, the hybrid one automatically. If the image is available, the image tag will be picked up automatically. I will just click on continue, and I will… let's keep it manual for now. Create a new service role.
PAUL: I will just click on Next.
PAUL: Give a name.
PAUL: Okay, hybrid one I'm giving for now.
PAUL: Then comes virtual CPU, rest of the configuration, see. Now, this add environment variable, if you want, you can add it here.
PAUL: Okay, really, like, if you want, you can add it here. Or later on, this particular service will be updated. So, in the script, I have this.
PAUL: If you really look into the script.
PAUL: my app runner script. So, there, if you look here, AWS AppRunner creates service, service name, like, create the service if it doesn't exist.
PAUL: So, this will be taken care of. So, you don't need to pass the environment variable, or if you want, you can do that.
PAUL: Totally. Options up to you. Just be sure the name should be exactly the same one. Don't use my name.
PAUL: Use the name which is available here, in your mean file, deploy.yml, app runner service link, please use that service.
PAUL: Okay, now this part is done, let's move ahead to the next part.
PAUL: Here, the information that you are getting it here, copy this one.
PAUL: Okay, and go back to your GitHub, and paste it in your environment variable. So, I have my GitHub.
PAUL: Where is Kita?
PAUL: Not here, I think.
PAUL: Here it is.
PAUL: Project, project, project, project, CD update, yes.
PAUL: Go to Settings, go to your…
PAUL: secrets, actions, from here. Now, add this particular information here.
PAUL: If you really try to compare the information, it's the same information. So if I really show you…
PAUL: Ctrl-N. Now, this I have copied from there. Okay, and…
PAUL: Initially, like, it needs to be created. If it is created, then you can actually get the role, from your terminal. Like, last time I was getting this one.
PAUL: Okay, so pretty much same information.
PAUL: Then you see, the information is exactly the same. One, you can get it from the UI, or you can get it. Just be sure the access rule is created. If it is not created, you might get an error.
PAUL: AppRunner, app runner, please create the app runners.
PAUL: ECR, automatically, it will be taken care of, Amit Kumar.
PAUL: even apprunner will be automatically taken care of, but you need the access rule. So that's why, for getting the access role, you can do it. Otherwise, from your terminal also, you can create an access role using JSON file. Anybody has done that previously? Like, creating a trust policy.json.
PAUL: Melan, just now I showed you how I created it.
PAUL: Do you want me to show the step again?
PAUL: feet.
PAUL: I'm going back.
PAUL: Again, the app runner.
PAUL: Okay, this is create a service.
PAUL: Container registry, ECR, again selecting the repo. Key and a hybrid image LED.
PAUL: Okay, let's pick up the latest one, continue. This part is done. I'm clicking here, Create New Service Rule. Done. I will click on next.
PAUL: Pass the name, which is mentioned in your script.
PAUL: Okay, so in the script, it's written, rack event app hybrid. Just pause that.
PAUL: Okay, sorry. This is the name.
PAUL: Courtney.
PAUL: This name, just copy it from here, and pass it.
PAUL: Okay, 1B CPU, two things. Rest of the things, you can keep it same.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Yes, you need a paid plan.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, just you need to click on next, you'll be getting this ECR Access Rule.
PAUL: Okay, from here, you just need to copy this information and paste it in your secret.
PAUL: And you can just do something like create and deploy.
PAUL: Okay, for me, this particular name is already taken, because I already have an existing service.
PAUL: Okay, in your case, you'll be getting that ECR access role. I hope, for everybody, it is clear how to get that ECR access role.
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: No. I think, no, you can't do this in free tare.
PAUL: after deployment, delete it instantly. The idea is that it should be up and working, as you saw, similarly, because I think, for me, all the configuration is done. In your case, only this secret was missing, so I told you how to get this particular secret.
PAUL: Cost is less than $0.2.
PAUL: Even less than that, I think, because initially, if you try to delete that.
PAUL: this part is hard. CI-CD part is hard. You just need to…
PAUL: make yourself do it 3 times, 4 times, 5 times automatically. Because a lot of new things that we are talking today, so we'll just keep it till this part. Because I know CI and CD, really, like, for many new students, it will be…
PAUL: tough to do this. But, just follow the steps. The steps are simple. I have provided you the scripts, so it should be up and working.
PAUL: Can you post the name of the repo secret for AppRanner? Already it's done, no, please check Notion.
PAUL: I think in Notion, it's already, I've given the name. This one, AppRunner.
PAUL: AppRunner, ECR Access Role ARM.
PAUL: Because, right now, I've just created the role from the UI. Otherwise, you can do it from the terminal, also, the other way. The same thing that you will be getting.
PAUL: Akel is asking, where are we using the API key? Here we are using… no?
PAUL: Opium, E-I-E-P-I-G.
PAUL: When I create the service, it looks for the image. First check, the image is available or not. That is the first check. If the image is not available, it means that something is wrong.
PAUL: In the YML file.
PAUL: Here, I'm passing runtime environment variables and all those environment variables.
PAUL: Credentials not loaded, please check your action. If somebody is getting this error.
PAUL: This error means… okay, I'm just showing you the error.
PAUL: Many of you might get it. If somebody's getting this error.
PAUL: Simply, it means that there is some issue with the environment variables that you have passed.
PAUL: Please do have a check.
PAUL: Because there is no way to debug.
PAUL: I cannot directly say, otherwise you have to add a lot of eco-statements.
PAUL: And through that, you can check.
PAUL: Alright. Now, whenever you are looking into this CI file, what is the main thing that you have to do? Because here, in the CI file, nothing that you have to change, only the branch. If I come to deploy, in the deploy, you have to just pass here the RAG system.
PAUL: hybrid. Just be sure it matches with your ECR repo name. If it doesn't match us, it will throw you an error.
PAUL: AppRunner, service name can be anything that you can pass.
PAUL: During the creation of the service, these variables will be used.
PAUL: So, Amit, if you are getting that the RAC Q&A system does not exist, it means what? You have to pass the correct NCR repo name. So, please change that.
PAUL: In line number 14, you have to do the update.
PAUL: And I think during your ECR repo creation, you should remember what is the variable, otherwise you can go to your AWS
PAUL: Where is AWS?
PAUL: Yes, here. You can go to your ACR service and check what is the name that you have passed.
PAUL: do the verification, at least. When you take my script, okay, in my script, few things can be based on my system, but if you're creating a repo, you can give your own private name, or some other name, how will I know that? Okay, so just be sure you are configuring… configuring that part.
PAUL: AppRunner Service, the same service that you have created. Please use the same name.
PAUL: Once the service is created, you can execute the same command in your local also.
PAUL: Okay, this command that I've shared with you in Notion, it can be executed in your local machine. You will be getting the result.
PAUL: AWSIM get roll this particular command. The same output that you will be getting, which you need to pass it in your secrets.
PAUL: CI.YML, the format is YML, not YAML.
PAUL: Viraj.
PAUL: Okay, Murthaza is telling everything is working for me, app run or endpoint, okay. I know you are good in AWS, so no issues for you.
PAUL: But let's look into some others. Amit is telling, ECR is showing with hybrid only. Yes, if it is hybrid, see, it doesn't matter what's the name. You know you have created with what name. You have to pass the correct name, that's the only thing.
PAUL: just be sure this name with your deploy.yml, this name matches.
PAUL: this… 2 should match.
PAUL: Can you show me how you created the environment variables? All right?
PAUL: You have to go to your GitHub.
PAUL: Okay, open the repo, click on Settings.
PAUL: From settings, you will be getting here your, secrets and variables.
PAUL: Click on actions, pass all the environment variables that I have told you.
PAUL: As simple as that. Now here, this app runner service rule, if I'm telling that I want to edit it, from, where you'll be getting the information.
PAUL: this particular information, I told you during the,
PAUL: AppRunner service. When you created your app runner service.
PAUL: Okay, so for example, you are creating the service. Let me just show you again.
PAUL: Let's pick up some image for now. Hybrid, let us continue. Manual, use the existing rule, fine.
PAUL: Okay, create a new role, let's go with.
PAUL: Alright, now, in this particular case, if I go ahead with the name… now, this name, I will try to match it with the name of my
PAUL: This one, RackQuil. Now, this service is already up and running for me, so I'm just adding one. You don't need to add one.
PAUL: Alright, now here, if I go next, you will see that you will be getting this access loop. This, you can copy.
PAUL: Okay? And just be sure you are doing a create and deploy.
PAUL: And then paste it here, in your .env. As simple as that. So, not here, where here. You have to just paste this value, and you have to update the secret.
PAUL: This is the way of adding the secrets.
PAUL: There are no other ways of adding.
PAUL: For now. This, you have to do it manually.
PAUL: Yes, majorly, because once the deployment is done, then I can say that yes. But for how many operates working? Few people have told that, yes, it's working, and the application is deployed. What about others?
PAUL: Okay, getting few error messages, debug.
PAUL: I'm getting this error.
PAUL: You exceeded your current quota, Deepak, please don't send me these errors now. This is related to your OpenAI API key.
PAUL: in… you have to get open, credits. CD going on, alright. How many of you are into the CD stage? First of all, tell me. Like, the push is done successfully, the image is available. Then the app runner service is working. Let's take one.
PAUL: One of you. Okay. So, let me just stop sharing. Let's take a student. I think it will be better to repeat the steps two to three times, so that others can do.
PAUL: Rajat, so I think you were there, Rajat. So, tell me, in your case, where you were stuck, start sharing.
PAUL: I think you can unmute yourself, I added you. Yes, tell me.
Rajat Khanna: Yes, so I'm sharing right now. So, first of all, like, if I try to add, the actions…
PAUL: not added. First add, then only we can do anything. You add?
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so, names, where I need to pick, those names.
PAUL: Check Notion, open Notion.
PAUL: Yes, majorly. The class discussion with respect to… because the deployment is done, then go in.
PAUL: Okay, configure the settings in the meantime. Rahul, I will come to you.
PAUL: Yes, Rahm, tell me.
Rahul Parihar: Hey, Paul, so can I… can I share my screen, real quick?
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes.
PAUL: start shooting.
PAUL: In your case, till which part is it done?
Rahul Parihar: So, I… I kind of… I wanted to… I'm already done with most of… where do I get my ARN request?
PAUL: Not only I told her no.
Rahul Parihar: Create an app runner service.
PAUL: why you are going to AIM.
Rahul Parihar: AppRunner Service, under.
PAUL: AppRunner, search for AppRunner. In the search button, search for AppRunner. This is a different service, which helps you to run applications.
PAUL: Okay? Now click on Create a Service.
Rahul Parihar: Create an apprentice?
PAUL: Now, is your container available?
Rahul Parihar: Yes, it is available.
PAUL: Alright, then, select Container Image URI, click on Browse.
PAUL: Select your repo.
PAUL: For active on your system, choose the image tag, image is notable.
PAUL: The first part, please try to push the image automatically, which we'll take care of.
Rahul Parihar: So, image pushing part is where I'm having challenge. You know, when I'm actually trying to build the image.
Rahul Parihar: Over here, you know, so with my… with my, I'm able to run… the image locally.
Rahul Parihar: However, when I'm trying to access, access my local… Local documents…
Rahul Parihar: and if I'm executing, say, any of the… any of the service health check, you know, it's… it's failing. The reason it is… it was failing because.
PAUL: Alright, fine, I got your problem. First of all, check in your local, everything should be up and working. Once your local issue is solved, then only you can move ahead and go ahead for the deployment. If something is happening, though you can do the deployment successfully, but again, the routes won't be working there.
Rahul Parihar: So yeah…
PAUL: I'll be repeating that step.
PAUL: Just wait one second.
PAUL: So, like, tell me for how many of you in the EE are the images available. That is the first step.
PAUL: And they can raise their hand, I can allow them to share their screen.
PAUL: Because I need to sh… images there, but free plan, okay, free plan block, fine.
PAUL: Rohit, alright. In your case, the image is available. I will add Rohit for now.
PAUL: Because, first check.
PAUL: Rahul, in your local, everything should be up and working. Once the local check is done, then once you start the deployment, your emails should be at least pushed.
PAUL: Once the image is pushed, then come to the AppRunner service. So, step by step, three steps are there. So, one that you need to look into.
Rohit Srivastava: So, yeah, so Rangshu, my image is pushed, and… So, service is also created? Yeah, sure. Just give me a second, please.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, can you see?
PAUL: Yes, I can see.
Rohit Srivastava: So, looks like… all is.
PAUL: Yes, yes, fine. Performing health check on protocol TCP. It means that at least that part has started, this is fine. There is no issue.
Rohit Srivastava: And the other thing is, on the GitHub, which of the things… I mean, this ARN needs to be copied, right?
PAUL: Okay, yes, not this one.
Rohit Srivastava: Go back. Before creating the surveys, you should. Go back to the service.
PAUL: Delete this one.
PAUL: Delete.
PAUL: Yes.
Rohit Srivastava: Alright.
PAUL: Because, again, the port, in your case, right now, the port, I think, which is being used, it is…
Rohit Srivastava: 8018. Yeah, I know, I know. Just, I mean, how do I delete it? It's not…
PAUL: Once that deployment is done, then only you can delete.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, so I think it's still deploying, it's in progress, yeah.
PAUL: Tell me, did you got that ARN? When you are creating, then only you get that option. Click on services, or use the command that I have shared.
Rohit Srivastava: Which command can you please…
PAUL: In Notion, in Notion.
Rohit Srivastava: Notion, alright. Yeah.
Rohit Srivastava: Hmm, just give me a sec.
Rohit Srivastava: Oops.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, motion, yeah.
PAUL: Is that.
Rohit Srivastava: This one?
PAUL: No, no, reload the page, reload the page.
PAUL: Okay, yes, that IAM get role, IAM, below, below, below, app, this, come on, take this.
Rohit Srivastava: Hold it, hold it just a minute, hold on.
Rohit Srivastava: I'm just kidding.
PAUL: Copy and paste it in your terminal, you'll be getting the secret.
Rohit Srivastava: Interested.
Rohit Srivastava: Oops.
Rohit Srivastava: Just check the starting 00, I think, something right there. Yeah.
Rohit Srivastava: No, that was wrong. Terminal route.
PAUL: Okay, he's got his information, this you have to copy-paste exactly in your GitHub.
Rohit Srivastava: And… Please, again, what variable will it be? Sorry, sorry for…
PAUL: No, no, no, in Notion only, the way.
Rohit Srivastava: -Oh.
PAUL: It's also written on top.
PAUL: app runner.
Rohit Srivastava: ECL access. Okay, okay, thanks. Yeah, yeah, thank you, thank you.
PAUL: Okay.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah.
PAUL: Okay, now…
Rohit Srivastava: Alright.
PAUL: Others also, just let me know with respect to access role. How many of you are stuck in getting the secret?
PAUL: Is there anyone who is stuck in only getting the secret?
PAUL: Body, adjust… I'm, see, I'm now sharing my screen. Okay.
PAUL: with… I will stop your sharing.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, sure, thanks. Sorry about that.
PAUL: Just wait. See, again, I am telling you and repeating myself.
PAUL: So step 3, so once… Begin.
PAUL: go back to your app runner service. So, in your case, there won't be any service. Okay, now you have to create a new service. So, create
PAUL: Now, before this.
PAUL: Please run the deploy so that at least the image is available. So I know that in my ACR, if I go here, the image is available.
PAUL: Okay, so always look into this images part, and from there, you can actually do the verification. Yes, the images are there. So here you can see the image is available. If the image is available, then only you can do the next step.
PAUL: Okay, so here, the image selection.
PAUL: So here, for example, if I select the repo.
PAUL: Automatically, you will see the latest. You don't have to do the selection here.
PAUL: Create a new if I'm going ahead. Next, give a name. This name should be exactly the one that you are passing it here. Then later on, it can be updated also. Otherwise, update will fade.
PAUL: Okay, here.
PAUL: Now, leave all these things empty for now. Okay, click on next, and just be sure you are getting this one.
PAUL: ECR access role. This, you have to copy, paste where? In your GitHub, here.
PAUL: Okay, and then please update your secret. Is this part clear for everyone?
PAUL: From where you'll be getting the app runner ECR access role ERN.
PAUL: Alright, I have repeated myself, okay? So now, let's look into some other students also.
PAUL: No, yes, so simply you can… now, you can let me know in the chat what is the problem, and based on that, I can tell you.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, I'm sharing, I have added all the keys.
PAUL: Novrint.
Rajat Khanna: Now, what I need to do next?
PAUL: Commit.
Rajat Khanna: No, no, it's, means commit is already there, so I have added, these.
PAUL: Again, you have to commit.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, this entire pipeline, it means that any…
PAUL: Thing is changed in your codebase, then again the deployment will take place.
PAUL: Everything was…
Rajat Khanna: There is no, there is no rerun, like, we can, re-run this file again.
Rajat Khanna: If we are.
PAUL: to actions. From there, you can see a rerun option.
PAUL: Generally, through commits, we do detect it.
PAUL: But, you can, click on, like, deploy to AWS, that part.
PAUL: And try to rerun that.
Rajat Khanna: No, so from here, I have not added, this, this one, so, from… First, you run the deployment, then only the image will be pushed.
Rajat Khanna: That's what would nothing be…
PAUL: doing it.
Rajat Khanna: Nothing needs… Okay.
PAUL: it will be added. If you push the image. If the image is not pushed, then how you will pass it, German?
PAUL: Pink.
Rajat Khanna: Where is the option of February?
PAUL: Just make another commit from GitHub, as simple as that.
PAUL: Change something, just a small thing in Markdown file, add a comment or something like that, really doesn't matter.
PAUL: what all needs to be deleted already. Now, you do it. Okay. In the meantime, I will start the deleting part. It's the most important part of this session. Everybody, please don't make all your services up and running.
PAUL: You will be getting charged.
PAUL: Alright, so first of all, with respect to your deletion, so as you can see here, the service that I have, okay, so let's get the AppRunner service. I will just close the Docker image from my local machine. Let me make it clear.
PAUL: the hand here also, I would be just doing a clear.
PAUL: Now, the first thing is the service that you have created. So, let's look into that service once.
PAUL: So, whether the service, you can list it from the command line also. There are a few commands, like AWS AppRunner List Services.
PAUL: So here you will see the deployment that I have done is successfully available, which is RAG UND App Hybrid. If you really look into, okay, RAG UND App Hybrid, pretty much the same name.
PAUL: Now, this deployment is successful, now the question comes of deleting this.
PAUL: In the next step, I will just select AWS AppRunner Delete Service.
PAUL: Okay, so hyphen US East 1… Let me just…
PAUL: take that entire thing in one shot. We cannot see, just, check.
PAUL: I have selected my desktop 3 only. Can you guys see?
PAUL: Please provide a confirmation.
PAUL: I use this command, app runner list services icon region US East 1, using which you can actually list the services. Then simply delete the services also. To delete the service, what you need.
PAUL: If you really look into hyphen hyphen service hyphen ARN. Now, this ARN that you have for this particular service, it should be exactly the same.
PAUL: So, what I will do, I will copy from here to this C8. Okay, copy. I won't be… I'm not using the EI, otherwise you can use the EI, that EY also.
PAUL: I will paste it here. Now I know this particular information is available. Now the service will be deleted.
PAUL: Okay, it takes few time, alright, fine.
PAUL: Okay, alright. Now, let me do, again, a list service, just to do a confirmation that the service is available. Okay, I can see. Let's wait for some time, and then I will do it again.
PAUL: Operation in progress, fine.
PAUL: Okay, I'm sharing the command, don't worry.
PAUL: So, first of all, get… okay, so these commands, I will keep it in a separate put block.
PAUL: AppRunner, list service. Once the service is available, then in the next step comes your delete one.
PAUL: So, for deletion, you need the ARM.
PAUL: the service AI.
PAUL: Now, this information that I'm sharing.
PAUL: You have to change according to your own ARM.
PAUL: Otherwise, simply delete it from the UI. Nothing.
PAUL: Okay, now this ARN I'm deleting because this is my ARN. You have to pass your own ARN, okay? So this hyphen hyphen service, hyphen ARN, this parameter, you'll be getting it once you have executed this command of list services. So, from list services, you will be getting this entire thing, which you need to pass it.
PAUL: Is this part clear?
PAUL: this information.
PAUL: So, first, dual list service.
PAUL: Okay, and then delete it.
PAUL: Otherwise, delete it from the UI also, that simple. Click, click, click, done. You don't need to execute any commands. So, whichever way you like it, you can do it.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, you can see that I deleted it. It takes some time to do the deletion, but successfully, the deletion is done. Image, no charge. Image for repos, nothing will be charged, don't worry. But, like, somebody might say that I want to delete the repo also.
Rajat Khanna: Like.
PAUL: In that case, you can do that. For that, also, I'm sharing the command.
PAUL: Okay, so I've deleted my app runner service, so there is nothing. So, using this command, you can do the deletion. Just be sure you are passing the correct name.
PAUL: Names are important, guys. Okay, so here I will just keep it star. Okay, E-O-A-R-N. Don't directly copy-paste it.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay.
PAUL: please pass your own URI.
PAUL: Now, the other command that you have here is ECR delete triple.
PAUL: Using this command, and just be sure you are passing the current… the correct ECR, repo name.
PAUL: So, for example, in my case, that eponym was this one.
PAUL: Q&A system hybrid. I will copy this one, hybrid. Okay, I will, go here.
PAUL: I think this one…
PAUL: Alright, now this is the command that I have. Now, before that, if you want to really check into your reports.
PAUL: AWS Describe.
PAUL: I think, AWS… ECR…
PAUL: Describe repositories, okay? So, using this, you can actually see what are the repositories which are available in your system. So, I created this one, RATQ and a System Hybrid.
PAUL: Simply, I can delete this.
PAUL: So, for that, I will take this command. You can do from all clicks, click, clicks.
PAUL: Okay, but I feel commands are much…
PAUL: handy most of the times. So here, I will pass…
PAUL: This one, Q&A system hybrid, now it will be deleted.
PAUL: Okay, now this is deleted. Now, again, if I run the describe repose, you will see that
PAUL: This time, only one result that you got. Okay, and which is my other repo. This also, I can delete it. Okay, the hybrid RAG API. But, our main idea, to delete the repo, as well as the image and the app runner service, everything is done. So it's pretty much clean, now you can simply, like, close your AWS.
PAUL: There are… for IAM users, they don't charge you.
PAUL: So it's not necessary. You change your IAM user. Going forward, you can keep the same IAM user.
PAUL: I have done the deletion for AppRunner, as well as for ECR. All the commands, I have pasted it here. So, step by step, you can do it.
Rajat Khanna: Paul, can I share now? The image is, deployed?
PAUL: Alright, just coming to you. This command, I think it was missing, let me paste it in Notion.
PAUL: Yes, Mantraj.
PAUL: For you, all the deployments are done, please let me know. People with issues, don't worry, I will start looking into the issues. So, everything I have updated in Notion, the major commands which needs to be executed. Alright, Rajat, now start sharing.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Rajat Khanna: So, now it is, deployed here.
PAUL: Hmm, it is. Now, go back to your app runner service.
PAUL: background or service.
PAUL: Here's a needle.
PAUL: Aniroth, for you, everything is working?
PAUL: Yes, alright, great. For people for whom everything is working, okay, they can drop, because nothing that I will discuss, I will just look into the issues now.
PAUL: Yes, click on Create Act on the service.
PAUL: Yes. Browse. Click on browse.
PAUL: Choose the repo.
PAUL: Okay? Yes, let us automatically it gets detected. Click on continue.
PAUL: Deployment, keep it manual, create a new service role.
PAUL: Create a new service role.
PAUL: Yes, click on next.
PAUL: Okay, now pass the service name that you have mentioned in your DP.
PAUL: Yes, now, go below, go below, go below.
PAUL: Okay, and now click on next, next, next.
PAUL: Now, from here, you are getting the access rule. This access rule, you have to paste it in your GitHub Secrets.
PAUL: Alright, I will come to one by one.
PAUL: That ARN.
PAUL: Pass it.
Rajat Khanna: What's the name?
PAUL: Above the command, the first one, apprender is.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, now click… go and click on next, next, next, next, next. Create and deploy.
PAUL: Now, see, the services are already available in your case.
PAUL: Okay? Later on, it will, basically update it.
PAUL: So, now, we have to rerun.
PAUL: Also… Once this part is done, it will fail. Okay, then do a new deployment.
PAUL: make a new commit, and push it. Okay, and then let me know.
Rajat Khanna: And as per the traffic, traffic as in, I'll be redirecting to the URL, so how many URL hits I do, service I do, that only will be the chargeable in the AWS.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes. Right now, for similarly, less than 1,000, not to worry.
Rajat Khanna: Okay. Okay. Yeah, thank you.
PAUL: Find.
PAUL: Now, people with problems, they can come one by one.
PAUL: Okay, please, let me know in the chat.
Rajat Khanna: Paul, just one last question, like, when I can connect with you, in weekdays regarding that mail…
PAUL: Probably, like, the timing will be night only, after 7.30pm.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, yes. So, first of all, let's start with Milint. Milind, as you told, I need help. Milint, I am adding you to panelist. Please start sharing your screen. Then, Saurabh Verma, give me a chance. Saurabh, I'm also adding you to panelist.
PAUL: Nagapam, okay, Nagapam also, I will add you to panelist. Few people I've added, so let's look into one by one.
milind kulkarni: Didn't see my screen?
PAUL: No, I cannot see.
milind kulkarni: Nice, there you go.
milind kulkarni: Alright, hold on, it's sharing the wrong screen, hold on.
milind kulkarni: Yeah, okay.
milind kulkarni: Can you see it now?
PAUL: Yes.
milind kulkarni: Okay, so I had added an environment here. I removed it just now.
PAUL: Where you created, I told go to GitHub Secrets, through that, you are accessing this one. Alright, to… okay, I think it will be picked up.
PAUL: Separately. I asked you not to… finally updated an environment.
milind kulkarni: I had created under environment variable also, but it wasn't become picking up slide till that under environment created. But even after I do that, I can do it back, no problem.
PAUL: Because you are an admin, it will have the access. Okay, not a big deal, but add that ERN.
PAUL: Access…
milind kulkarni: No, no, right now, when I'm going to actions…
PAUL: My CD pipeline doesn't work. It gives an error saying that credential would not be loaded. Yeah, it means that, simply, credential doesn't… is loaded, it means that that is the problem from there only. Please pass it the way that I have told.
PAUL: what they know what?
milind kulkarni: Great.
milind kulkarni: Under here, actually one wheel? Yes, yes, yes, yes.
milind kulkarni: So, peer-only…
PAUL: Why in variables… see, right now, don't expose that, just new repo, add all the things that are remaining.
milind kulkarni: Here.
PAUL: DS.
milind kulkarni: Okay.
milind kulkarni: So all, all, all should be there.
PAUL: Yes, everything. Everything that I have shared, all those things should be there. Total 7, I think, secrets are there. Please pass everything.
milind kulkarni: Are they? All right.
PAUL: Morish, hardest structure.
PAUL: I would share an item.
milind kulkarni: It is.
PAUL: Yeah, yeah.
PAUL: We'll do the configuration heartache,
PAUL: I have added you to panelist, okay.
PAUL: Biffen Samiksha, don't worry, I will come to you.
PAUL: In the panelists, others, please do share, like, Saurabh is there.
saurabh verma: Yeah, so can I share my screen?
PAUL: Yes, yes, please go over it.
saurabh verma: Okay, thank you.
saurabh verma: I'm sharing.
PAUL: Santoshumargi, I will come to you, don't worry. First, I will…
PAUL: That is fine. Then I will come. Yes.
saurabh verma: So, I'm facing issue in the CI part, so that's why I didn't disturb in the between. So, this is my repository.
PAUL: Yes.
saurabh verma: If we go to, GitHub, workflow, it has a CIYML file.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. First of all, you have a folder within that, another folder, why you are using this structure?
PAUL: Your dot slash workflow should be in the root.
PAUL: Hop your folder.
PAUL: Because of this structure, it will fail, it will not work only.
saurabh verma: Actually…
PAUL: I hope you get my point. Why you are using RAC Q&A Project SKV? What is the purpose of using that?
saurabh verma: Okay, this was the folder which I pushed.
PAUL: No, it doesn't work in that GitHub action. It has to be on the main.github folder has to be in the root way, so it won't work. Yeah, to change your complete folder structure.
saurabh verma: So, it should be this one, the RCU.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes, that has to be the main reporter.
saurabh verma: Okay, let me do that, then I'll come back. Sorry about that.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Okay, let me share my screen here.
PAUL: Yes, please, proceed.
PAUL: Please maintain the structure, guys, that I have shared in class.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Thanks, Paul, for teaching, but I just lost the way before the CA part itself, okay? So, here I am trying to push the code, okay? Here, I'm trying to put the commit, but in the kit, I couldn't see the list of all the files and everything.
PAUL: What have you done? You created, you cloned, exactly what have you done?
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Just I'm… okay, these are all my files, okay, here. So, I'm trying to push all the files to get.
PAUL: So, see, CI, CD, leave it.
PAUL: Okay, I'm not worried about CICT now. Just tell me…
PAUL: the repo part. So, like, you have the code in your local machine, you are telling. Yes. Now, my request is, push it, or fork my report. Do one thing at least.
PAUL: Now, whichever way you want to do it, you do it.
PAUL: Because I'm not teaching you how to push the code now.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Okay, I'm trying to push all this code,
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Okay.
PAUL: To push a code, what is the bare minimum require, thing that you need? Tell me. First.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Aww.
PAUL: I will move ahead. You need a repo?
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Yes.
PAUL: And right now, from here, your account is authenticated.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Yes, account is authenticated.
PAUL: Pantos?
PAUL: Okay, Santo, just check you are using the correct file or not. If you are using the wrong file, you will be getting that error of runtime environment variables.
PAUL: Just wait, I think,
PAUL: Getting a call, yes. So, first of all, push the code, because this is the bare minimum, this is… there is no CICD. Or take a fork. If you don't want to do anything, please take a fork. That is the easiest way in class the students have done. Whichever way you feel you need to sort this part.
PAUL: Because this is day one thing. There is nothing, like, after one month.
PAUL: Because right now, what is your main goal? To post the code?
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Yes, yeah, pushing the quarter.
PAUL: Then please do that.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: And please use the correct files. I feel this file is incorrect.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Oh, the files is incorrect, is it? Okay.
PAUL: Please, see, I have shared that repo, please open my repo, first of all.
PAUL: My report. The report that I have shared, go to Notion, open that link.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Yeah, this is SWAT report.
PAUL: Yes, project class, click fork on top of that.
PAUL: No, no, no, click on Rack Project Class, RAC Project Class.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Yeah.
PAUL: Click on right to the class.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Okay, huh?
PAUL: And do a fork of this one.
PAUL: Fork, fork, F-O-R-K.
PAUL: Fork.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Oh, okay.
PAUL: Entire thing will be copied in your case. Delete your own, otherwise it will throw an error here.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Okay, fine, yeah, sure, I will do that, okay.
PAUL: Always take a fork, that's the fastest way, remember.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: SPF.
PAUL: Okay.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Okay, okay, one way is push another port. Okay, thank you, yeah.
PAUL: Viraj, mildew regarding hybrid rag assignment, okay, we have an assignment, name advanced learning. Alright, I will look into that mail, okay, then I will respond back. Others in the panelists, please proceed. Whoever is there in the panelists, they can…
Hardik Khanna: I'll share my screen quickly.
PAUL: ESP people are there, weapons, Kiran naga, Santosh, just wait, I will come.
Hardik Khanna: My screen was.
PAUL: Okay, huh, Jalu, push is done. Now, deploy to apprunner is failing. Failed to load the service, your application drops. Okay, fine, let's get back.
PAUL: Okay, good internet.
PAUL: Here, it's telling… the… TCP, just wait.
PAUL: Okay, alright, deployment. Go back there.
PAUL: In GitHub Actions. Don't show me this email.
PAUL: Click on actions, and show me those logs of your, deployment logs.
PAUL: That is more important.
PAUL: Yes, click again.
PAUL: Okay? Just wait.
PAUL: run… okay, click there, that run AWS Update Services there.
Hardik Khanna: So, after one time fail, I, deleted and again tried to recreate it, but, it's the same issue.
PAUL: An error occurred, invalid state exception when calling update service. Service cannot be updated in the current state.
PAUL: If it is not able to update, you have to generally delete it.
Hardik Khanna: Yes, I tried, but… I have not rerun this thing.
PAUL: But why say it was failing again.
PAUL: No, this is fine, because, just wait, let me just look into why…
PAUL: Because the service already exists in your case, so that update operation will take place. So I'm just looking into that update. Just wait one, let me look into my GitHub.
PAUL: I will tell you exactly that log.
PAUL: Actions… I think the second one was deploy.
PAUL: Output, update, if exists, create.
PAUL: Alright, can you do one thing?
PAUL: Just, delete that service.
Hardik Khanna: Delete, okay.
PAUL: Delete, and then, do a commit again. Let me see that entire thing.
Hardik Khanna: Delete this one.
PAUL: Though it will take some time…
Hardik Khanna: Yeah, it's standard.
PAUL: I'll do the commit once again now.
PAUL: Janika, what command build and push to is here?
PAUL: There is no command, you have to just do a commit.
PAUL: Automatically, the entire pipeline will be triggered.
PAUL: Okay, do just a small change, add something, A, B, C, D, and just do a commit.
PAUL: Done? Alright, now go back and let's wait for the CI and CD part.
PAUL: This part really takes time, like, whenever I do my own testing, it might take 2-3 hours for me also.
PAUL: So, it's fine.
Hardik Khanna: Somehow, it is directly pointing to CI.YML.
PAUL: Yes, first CI will work, then only the next part.
Hardik Khanna: Okay, okay. So, I was trying to manually do the same running.
PAUL: Just wait, step by step, let's see.
PAUL: This part works, I know, and this is complex also for initially, like, teaching PICD, for beginners, it's a bit hard. If somebody doesn't have any AWS info, or Git info, really.
PAUL: Jenkins and more complex. GitHub Actions is at least easier.
PAUL: Jenkins is really more complex, I can say.
PAUL: This will take time, nothing you can do, you have to wait.
Hardik Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: Just sit and watch. Generally, you will get emails, I think.
PAUL: Email notification will come whenever a build will fail.
Hardik Khanna: Oh, okay.
PAUL: In the meantime, anybody else want to share their screen? They can. Ardik is sharing. Anybody from panelists who want to share? Otherwise, I will get from…
PAUL: The next list from our attendees.
PAUL: Nobody, Milanth, Hardi, Rahul, okay, alright, now let's pick up.
PAUL: Someone, let's go ahead with VIPIN.
PAUL: The plane, I have added you to panelist.
PAUL: Shubhath, I have added you to panelist.
PAUL: Santosh, I have added you to panelists. Okay, Janika, Naga, and a few people, I will come to you.
PAUL: Even directly start shedding.
PAUL: whoever is joining. So, Santosh, Pepin, Savash, anyone.
Vipin Tiwari: Hey, hi Paul, we've been this side.
PAUL: Yes, delete the image. See, like, the container image received is not required, you won't be charged. Okay, but delete the app runner service. AppRunner is a very costly service. Just be sure your app runner is deleted.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Please proceed ahead with the screen sharing.
Vipin Tiwari: Paul, can you hear me, between the side?
PAUL: Yes, yes, I can.
Vipin Tiwari: Paul, I mean, I don't have an AWS account. Earlier, I had created But.
PAUL: Okay, Raja, that's working for you now. Great, Raja. Alright, fine.
PAUL: Yes, so if you don't have an AWS account, you can do the same stuff in GCP also.
Vipin Tiwari: Because last time, I forgot to stop some of the services. I did an agent degree course, I think with you only, I created some.
Vipin Tiwari: deployed some services, but I've…
Vipin Tiwari: not forget, I was not able to delete where I can see the services somehow. I tried best, but I could not find her out, so I got some charge.
Vipin Tiwari: Some 15,000 dollar… 16,000 rupees, not dollar, so…
Vipin Tiwari: Now, I'm a little bit, afraid of creating AWS accounts, because they are asking credit… this debit card details.
Vipin Tiwari: I don't know how to…
PAUL: They will ask, nothing… see, to get, at least, you need. Nothing that I can do. Even for GCP, they will ask credit card, or UPI somewhere through an auto-pay.
PAUL: Nothing that we can do. Even, like, every month, even I pay bill for all my classes, my monthly bill will be less than 200 rupees.
PAUL: Okay. Okay. So, like, for every batch that I do. So, that is the main thing you need to take care. It means once the service is up, then please delete that also.
Vipin Tiwari: Okay, there's no way we can, just create the free one and use it, and then stop. I mean, not to stop it, I mean, by default, it should not charge anything. Like, in Azure, we have, right, $200 got credited, and we can keep using it, will not charge any extra thing.
PAUL: Yes, it won't be charging you at least extra.
PAUL: So, I will say that use a… see, if you're working with credit card laws, in your credit card, you can manipulate that, or you can add, like, debit at much riskier, just whatever that limit is there, reduce that limit to only 1000 rupees, and then start working, and that way, you know that you won't be getting overcharged also.
PAUL: That way, try to handle it.
PAUL: But at least create an AWS account that is,
PAUL: Bare minimum request, because we are taking it, because today I've shown you something in Next Step, most of the things will be very common. Probably the service will only change. AppRunner is easy to execute for any beginner, so I picked it up.
Vipin Tiwari: Okay, second thing is, when I'm running this Docker run, right, in my local, so I'm getting one very, error-like field required, pedantic…
Vipin Tiwari: And, yeah, so this is… Sherry is…
PAUL: share your screen, I need to look into the error.
PAUL: So right now, Santosh, you were telling me an error occurred, access denied when calling update service operation ARN IAM, user rack, user is not authorized to perform IAM pass role on resource, because no… show me your IAM user policies. Show me that. IAM users, exactly what is written, I need to look into that.
PAUL: Okay, go to IAM users, yes.
PAUL: Mmm… okay, one user is there, ranking user, you have created.
PAUL: Alright, add container APRA… Elastic container, EC2 container, why you have selected, okay?
PAUL: For now, I think majorly the major purpose… okay, just add for now, just initially, add permission. Click on Attach Policies directly.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Select the third one, admin.
PAUL: For now.
PAUL: Okay, so… just next, next.
PAUL: Okay, and show me your GitHub secrets once. GitHub secrets quickly.
Santosh Umargi: Yeah.
PAUL: Because right now, you have the admin access, so I think…
PAUL: It should be picked up. You can rerun it by taking a commit, you can do a rerun if you feel that all of your secrets are fine.
PAUL: Okay, so how many? 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7? Okay, alright, all the major secrets are there.
Santosh Umargi: Yeah, and I updated that.
PAUL: Melind, now the image is published and created the app runer. All right, yeah.
PAUL: Fine, this part is done. Alright, now, just do a commit, and let's see. Automatically, that trigger will take place.
Santosh Umargi: I rerun, or do the comment here?
PAUL: Just do a normal commit, okay, or rerun all jobs, or failed jobs only, you can do that.
Santosh Umargi: Okay.
PAUL: Done.
Santosh Umargi: Yeah.
Santosh Umargi: What was the…
PAUL: It was a permission issue, I think, because…
Santosh Umargi: Yeah, yeah. Actually, earlier, no, I was referring to, this one, no? You given this.
Santosh Umargi: This one. It is not updated, you have, like, a different repo.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, see, that project is different, and this one is a bit different. Okay. Yeah, the main idea was to share that project with you, because here I have not talked about test cases, really.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, okay, good.
PAUL: For me, test cases is not my partial job of some other team, but I've kept one sample there. Similarly, I kept the UI also, because the UI part I'm not going to discuss. It's not the right thing. Okay, so that's why I've shown you that all the features, so very similar implementation here also.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, but these two files are different here, like, here it is only 112 lines, and it has, like, 2-4 file lines here in deployment.
PAUL: Yes, I know, because this class here, I'm using AWS commands.
PAUL: the default AWS environment variables was not getting picked up. Okay. That was the issue. So, last night, I even did 7 commits only to do one. It was failing. Then, after testing only, I've added.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, okay.
Santosh Umargi: So, I think now it is running, no? So, how to test, like, by, wait, wait.
PAUL: It takes time. Okay, okay. It takes time, 5 minutes.
Santosh Umargi: So, shall we get URL like same?
PAUL: Yes, here only we'll be getting the URL.
Santosh Umargi: Like this, no? Like…
PAUL: You will be getting the URL there only. You have to just look into the log.
Santosh Umargi: Okay. Attempt, like, when the attempt is close to 21.
PAUL: to 25, then you'll be getting the URL.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, okay, okay, yeah, thank you.
PAUL: Just wait, yes.
Santosh Umargi: Thank you.
PAUL: Next, we want to share, please let me know, Suwar.
Vipin Tiwari: Yeah, I'm stating one second.
PAUL: Okay, Vipen, Suvas, anyone, please proceed?
Vipin Tiwari: This is the Ravish I'm getting.
PAUL: This is a, field error. This is spied intake. Type missing. OpenAI API key is missing.
Vipin Tiwari: See, open API keys have been added here. Do I… quadrant key, I'm not added, because I don't have account here. Should I need to do it, or…
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes, without this, nothing will work. You have to pass Quadrant, you have to pass OpenAI.
Vipin Tiwari: Damigo…
PAUL: But again, but, okay, here, OpenAI fee field missing, then why it's selling OpenAI? Just be sure you are using capital O everywhere. Don't use the smaller version, okay? Because Quadrant URL also, you need to pass on Quadrant API key.
PAUL: Without this, the application won't work.
PAUL: We'll do those changes.
PAUL: Okay, next, it's just a key.
Vipin Tiwari: Who's right.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Holo.
Vipin Tiwari: And…
PAUL: in quadrants.
Vipin Tiwari: Huh.
PAUL: you need.
Vipin Tiwari: Okay, fine. One second thing is, while creating an account, right, do we need to upload this PAN card and.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes, bankrupt is required.
Vipin Tiwari: When God is required. Okay.
PAUL: Take your time. These clicks take time, so sit at least for 2 to 3 hours.
PAUL: Okay, so, and do the setup. Use the AWS account, and don't worry, we won't be using more than 300 to 400 rupees.
Vipin Tiwari: In our future classes, are you going to use AWS only, or something else?
PAUL: Every time AWS. See, I can always create sample scripts of GCP just to share with you, if you want. Right now, I've not done it, but the same thing that I have done it here, I can do it in GCP. Just, I will change one service.
PAUL: From AppRunner to Cloud Run.
PAUL: In GCP, directly. The same concept, everything is the same.
PAUL: the core logic. Only the name of the services will change. Here, I'm using ECR. There, I might be using Google Active Directory. That's the only change.
PAUL: Alright, so new joinees, Samiksha, I think somebody else also I have added.
Subhash: Hyper.
PAUL: Yes.
Subhash: Well, I'm able to access the AWS URL, and when I upload a document…
PAUL: Okay. Share and show me.
PAUL: Azure, a lot of changes are required.
PAUL: Okay, but, you can do that. You need majorly your artifact registry, that is one thing, and the…
PAUL: second service is, like, you can use, web apps, I think. Azure web apps are there, directly you can use that service.
PAUL: You have to change your CD file, only CD file changes required.
Subhash: later.
PAUL: So, Vash, right? How many services you are creating? Okay, yes, this is working, I can see.
Subhash: Yeah, so this is working, and…
Subhash: I can able to access this also, but when I upload the document, it is… I'm getting, like, document was uploaded.
PAUL: So, show me your Docker image, first of all. Run your Docker. Are you getting the same error? If you are getting the same error, you need to fix that.
PAUL: Before doing the deployment, you have to check, show me the Docker. In your local image, I think in your local system, there is a Docker image, run that Docker image, and show.
Subhash: Okay, I have stopped that, okay, maybe because of that.
PAUL: First, always do a check in your local. If everything is working in your local docker, then only do the push.
Subhash: Okay, okay, yeah, sure, I'll do that.
PAUL: Okay, otherwise, here you will be getting the logs also, like, you can look into the logs of AppRunner, and based on that, you can fix your application. But I will suggest always fix it in local limit.
PAUL: Like, from… once it reaches AWS, it means that you are assured that every route and everything is working in your system.
Subhash: Okay, sure, I'll take that.
saurabh verma: Can I see a mystery?
PAUL: Santosh, I think you have failed Santosh for.
Hardik Khanna: Even for me as well, the same error.
PAUL: Can I share my screen?
saurabh verma: I am.
PAUL: a lot of yes.
saurabh verma: Yes. So… So, this is the thing. Now…
saurabh verma: which I had, taken a fork, and, also in my local VS Code, And,
saurabh verma: If we go here…
saurabh verma: So, we have GitHub.
saurabh verma: Workflow.
saurabh verma: C-I-I-A-L. So this is the file. And I then made changes,
PAUL: First of all, taken a wrong fork. The one that I have shared today, please take that one. Don't pick up something from the Saturday table.
saurabh verma: Okay.
saurabh verma: Do I…
PAUL: Please, please pick up the correct ripple, this is the wrong one.
PAUL: Alright, now, next, whoever wants to share. I think Santosh and, like, whoever was getting the same issue.
Hardik Khanna: Can I share my screen quickly?
Hardik Khanna: Yeah, mine. Okay.
Hardik Khanna: Is it visible?
PAUL: Yes.
Hardik Khanna: Okay.
Hardik Khanna: So.
PAUL: updated already.
Hardik Khanna: It got filled, here.
PAUL: Okay, now, show me that, here, what is exactly the issue that is happening after attempt?
PAUL: Deployment failed with status creation failed.
PAUL: But why it's getting filled? Because currently the status is up and running.
PAUL: I've scrolled a little bit.
PAUL: Waiting for the service, because the service is created.
PAUL: And why it is failing.
PAUL: Alright, do one thing, go back to your app run.
Hardik Khanna: Yes.
PAUL: Okay, now, click on the service, rack event system hybrid.
Hardik Khanna: Nope.
PAUL: Okay, creation failed. Alright, this is the source.
PAUL: Here, it's telling that the, pulling the image, fine, successfully.
PAUL: Is it related to… Look for… look into the deployment logs. Right now, it's telling no.
PAUL: is… because by default, it uses 8080.
PAUL: Have you changed the boot anywhere?
Hardik Khanna: Nope.
PAUL: Alright, go back, go back to apprender. Here, these things are working. Now, click on, Deployment Logs.
Hardik Khanna: Meritas.
PAUL: Here's the deployment logs. Deployment logs.
PAUL: Below, below. Deployment logs, application logs.
PAUL: Okay, click on that.
PAUL: application image deployment is failing. Go back, go one step back, and look into the application logs.
PAUL: You have to check here the logs, and based on that, you need to fix what is the issue.
PAUL: Alright, now see, what error you are getting.
PAUL: Yeah, now based on this issue, you have to solve. This is a Python issue.
PAUL: That you need to care about.
Hardik Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: All right, how to thick.
Hardik Khanna: Okay, take it. I'll, I'll do it.
Samiksha Mahajan: Eyeball.
PAUL: Yes, some extra places proceed.
Samiksha Mahajan: Yeah, actually my issue is resolved.
Samiksha Mahajan: Great, sir. Thank you.
PAUL: Alright. Next, anybody from, like, Ideas.
Santosh Umargi: Same issue, like, huh, like…
PAUL: Take the application logs, as Opal Show me.
PAUL: Sometimes, if your application only doesn't start, it means that problem with your main Docker image.
Santosh Umargi: Well.
PAUL: Show me the application logs? App logs, app logs.
PAUL: App logs. Here only. Yes, scroll down, scroll down. First, he will be having deployment level logs, then application. Yes, go below.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, go below, go below the application logs.
PAUL: Hmm, same Python-related issue.
Santosh Umargi: Okay.
PAUL: We need to sort it out.
Santosh Umargi: Yeah.
PAUL: This is a Pythonic error, and I can see in the error quadrant EPA, those things. Just be sure you are passing the environment variable. If it is missing.
PAUL: you will get there. Other thing that you can do, see, even for, Hardik, for you and anywhere, okay, just,
PAUL: close this, and check directly from EY if you want to pass it. Because if you remember, when I was creating the service, I didn't pass
PAUL: that environment variable. All those 5 or 6 environment variables, I have automatically updated it, so from here also you can do.
Santosh Umargi: Okay. means, like, while creating, you are saying, like, while creating.
PAUL: You know, now also go to rack vendor service.
Santosh Umargi: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, and then go to configurations, I think somewhere in the… within your configurations here. Okay, this you have already passed.
PAUL: No, this says pickup from the… Okay, okay, if it has got pickup, then I feel that it is correct.
PAUL: Because most of the settings do a verification, don't expose and delete everything after the class, because as you have exposed written.
Santosh Umargi: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah, yeah, I will delete that.
PAUL: do a check, because this was the idea, that you don't pass it, that's why I kept it in the script, that it will be updated.
PAUL: sometimes you can do a rerun of that system, because you are getting a Python error, that your, that is not getting recognized either.
Santosh Umargi: There you go.
PAUL: URL, you need to take care of that Pythonic error from your side.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, okay. So, like, shall I check from the code side, or the first try to do the rerun?
PAUL: You can do, try to do a rerun once.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, okay.
Santosh Umargi: Or rerun all jobs last time I did only…
PAUL: just focus on the failed job. All jobs will take a lot of time, so just this one.
PAUL: Okay, now coming to Kiran… Then come Janika… Then Modasar… Then comes Good Jewel.
PAUL: Few people I have added.
PAUL: One by one.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, I will check, and we'll let you know.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Which one is also tongue?
PAUL: bullshit.
PAUL: people, Kiran, Muddhasar, one by one, you guys can go with it.
Mudassar Hakim: Hey, Paul, Budasar here. So, I think I'm good today with the session. I just wanted to plan a few things ahead, because there's a possibility I might be away next weekend. So, what is the plan for tomorrow?
PAUL: Tomorrow, I think we will start with Llama Index.
Mudassar Hakim: Now my next… okay, and what are you planning for the next weekend? 27? 20 years?
PAUL: Llama index continuation only, it will take place.
PAUL: Just check module-wise, I think, in your module, what is that? Let me go through the official syllabus Monster.
PAUL: are devast… Just wait.
PAUL: screen, this is desktop 3, your Notion, where is Notion? Notion? Yes.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, and in the meantime, others who… I heard somebody, poor fellow, lost $16,000 in that. There's something called as AWS budget. You can actually put a budget over there, and the moment that budget exceeds, or a certain threshold exceeds, you start getting a lot of emails.
Mudassar Hakim: and you still feel you need more tighter controls, you can create an IAM policy that will kill the instances for you as soon as there is a certain, you know.
Mudassar Hakim: Inactivity happening there.
Mudassar Hakim: That torso is possible.
PAUL: Now I think, just wait, Cinema's link is there, yeah.
PAUL: We will start with Lama Intense, and probably next week I'll be talking about
PAUL: Like, a little bit we'll start with hybrid rack, that, these things. Query engine, re-ranking, those topics will come, I think.
PAUL: Continuation, I think. Llama Index, it will go for 2 to 3 classes.
PAUL: Yes, 2-3 classes at least.
PAUL: Okay, okay, so Lama Index and… Because, see, the topics, few topics are there, like, hybrid, RAG, these things, no. Now, these things are automatically covered, I know, in my other section, when I'll be talking about, like, hybrid search. So, all these topics, I will be covering in one shot only.
PAUL: Okay, so that's right.
PAUL: Okay. Advanced chunking, I think later on, I think next week, probably Monday or next year, then I will discuss. But at least hybrid, because this content is based on that, because you guys have learned SnaveRag, now the idea is to proceed towards a little bit advanced, where we add the hybrid functionalities.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay, and the last point is, from your experience, Paul, what I've seen is that, even certain teams which I've seen, rather than directly acquiring an OpenAI key separately and, driving things, what they do is.
Mudassar Hakim: within the AWS ecosystem, or Azure ecosystem, they change the model from there itself.
PAUL: That's the way, in every company they do it.
Mudassar Hakim: Absolutely.
PAUL: First question, first answer, they have long-term contracts. Like, in Croatia also, we have 10 years of contract with AWS.
Mudassar Hakim: So I know that the price that I'm getting.
PAUL: If I directly take from OpenAI, he told me, AWS provided me something close to 67% cheaper. Similarly, it happens to organizations with there. So, it happens in that lobby of, like, where.
Mudassar Hakim: Yikes.
PAUL: CT or somewhere, they have some connections based on that. So it's the correct approach.
Mudassar Hakim: Right, so considering that happening, I was wondering if we would be going through that stuff, because I have seen some examples, did certain basic examples of using that model, creating it, Bedrock, for example.
PAUL: No, no, no, CCC. Creating and working with Red Rock, next class maybe I can do. It's just small, two lines of code.
PAUL: Okay, I can show you, tomorrow I will show you that.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, I mean, I'm just saying the kind of things we definitely… this is what we are going through is necessary, there's no doubt about that. But maybe as and when…
PAUL: My priority is showing you one API key. Later on, you might use anything in the future. So, really, I'm not aware about that. I know that only you have to change two lines of code, and I think by that time, every… in your development journey, you can easily do that, two lines of changes.
Mudassar Hakim: Got it.
PAUL: Okay, because, see, when I show you with OpenAI, and majorly for practical demos, it's good. But really, in my production work, even I don't use OpenAI, I use Anthony.
Mudassar Hakim: I'm taking this as a learning curve, to be very honest. What I was doing right.
PAUL: And in AWS, you have anthropic-based models, okay? The… I generally pick something from Cloud family, that is my favorite family, okay? So, like, I always pick up. So, if you want, I can show you an integration of, like, Lang Chain. Yeah, something of that sort. Or in Llama Index part, also, I can pick up better.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, if we can take that, that would be helpful, because, I mean, understanding that this is important, but that also, if you just go through it, in case.
PAUL: Alright, alright. Like, tomorrow only the first thing. I will show the integration with AWS Bedrock.
PAUL: or some textbook. Okay.
PAUL: Okay, alright, this part is done. Next, we want to share it.
PAUL: I think anyone… Kiran, if you want to share, Janiki, I think Jenika, Naga, then comes Saurabh. Okay, Saurabh, let me know your status. Which one?
PAUL: Everybody I have added in, one by one.
Kiran Rathod: I, politely, last week, I was not able to attend, so I was trying to, clone the project, which was shared last Saturday, and I was…
PAUL: No, no, don't clone that one. Clone the one that I've shared. See, last Saturday, whatever the manual code that we have written, that I have pushed it in the report. Saturday, the original report, there are a lot of other things are there.
PAUL: Okay, which really, like, for our discussion, it is not required, like, how to create UIs or other. There, I have provided the code for that. But the actual work that we have done, it was in today's report that I have shared.
PAUL: So please fork that trip.
Kiran Rathod: Okay, so in that case, I had created, I mean, I had taken the pull directly from your repo, and I can see that when I was trying to add the requirement, right, I'm getting the pbyproject.
Kiran Rathod: Therml file is not available.
PAUL: Yes, there is no… you have to do an UVP pencil hyphena requirement.
Kiran Rathod: No, but when I do the TV pip install.
PAUL: UVPIP install.
PAUL: Good side.
Kiran Rathod: Yeah, I'm getting Python error.
PAUL: Show me.
Kiran Rathod: Yeah.
PAUL: Python interpreter not found.
PAUL: These are all system-level issues. Anaconda… you have Anaconda 3 in your system.
Kiran Rathod: Yes, I do have that, yes.
PAUL: do it using Conda, not a problem. Do it using Conda for now.
Kiran Rathod: Okay, let me try, and I'll just get back here.
PAUL: Yes, because Python interpreter not found, really, like, I feel that it should be available.
PAUL: and .vnv, whether that is there or not. You can use Condor, that is the first step to install your dependencies, so please have a check on that.
Kiran Rathod: I'll try to install, and I'll get back. Thanks.
Kiran Rathod: And sometime now.
PAUL: Okay, now, I think somebody has joined me. So, can I share?
saurabh verma: Can I share my screen?
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, please start, start, start, solve.
saurabh verma: So, this is the latest code, that I have taken, and this is the latest reclass.
PAUL: Correct, correct, correct, correct.
saurabh verma: Nobody's cutting it?
PAUL: Yes. Correct.
saurabh verma: Okay.
PAUL: if…
saurabh verma: And then…
PAUL: Right.
saurabh verma: Then I made a small change in the README, okay?
PAUL: Okay, fine, fine.
saurabh verma: Then, over here, if I go to Actions.
PAUL: Actions, okay, alright?
saurabh verma: I could not see. Should I do once again?
PAUL: Yes, yes, just do a push, and then show me.
saurabh verma: Yeah, I'll do that right now.
PAUL: Just do a simple commit, and then let's see that whether it's getting activated or not. Main branch you have done, I think it's correct over here.
PAUL: Okay, Janika, you can also start sharing that a little, yes.
PAUL: Now, just do a push, and let's start with the flu.
PAUL: Now, this part is really, like, CICD, okay, in your initial class.
PAUL: Nobody teaches. In other batches, we teach it at the end, probably, if it's not an ops-related class. In MLOps, okay, like, LLM Ops, AIOps, in these type of operations, generally. So, majorly, this task is taken care of by DevOps team.
PAUL: there will be someone from MLOps, or somewhere. So, we don't do it. If you are working into MLOps, then only you need to take care of these type of stuff.
PAUL: Where everything has to be done by one.
PAUL: This is stuff I know for how many of you, like, if it is not working, go and watch the recording, at least. Two times, three times, and then, again, tell me tomorrow that, yes, this part is not working.
PAUL: Because even for me, when I was doing it back in, I think.
PAUL: In 2016 and 17, even GitHub Actions didn't came in the market.
PAUL: Then, I was using Jenkins, those pure DevOps stuff. But right now, with GitHub Actions, it's very, very easy.
PAUL: Anyone can do it.
PAUL: Because for Jenkins, the main problem that I feel, again, I have to run Jenkins in some another server.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why I don't prefer it.
PAUL: RAG agent TKI with Azure, I think agent ports with Azure, we will be, like, like, all agents part with cloud, there will be one course which will come in, but I won't be doing the recording.
PAUL: I think somebody else, probably after 45 days, Lonali, or 50 days.
PAUL: there will be one course where Bedrock Agents, Azure, Copilot.
PAUL: Okay, in GCP also, with ADK support, so those things, one course will come.
PAUL: Before that, I think that project will come right now. I think by next month, that project…
PAUL: Website will also be launched, where only projects will be there.
Jainika: Yes, I commit, just commit now.
PAUL: Sure, sure, sure, sure, Dr. Kamut.
PAUL: Saurabh, and your status, okay?
Jainika: Read me, I just… Make one commit.
PAUL: Okay, faint.
PAUL: You have all the environment variables set?
Jainika: No.
PAUL: Please do that.
PAUL: Okay, simply.
Jainika: without that, it will not work. I actually.
PAUL: I'm not…
Jainika: Not able to see the two runners.
PAUL: No, no, show me your settings part, first of all. Show me your settings.
PAUL: Click on Settings.
PAUL: Go to Actions.
PAUL: Security, security, scroll down. Environment variables, I think, scroll down, scroll down, down, secrets and variables.
PAUL: Click on actions.
PAUL: You have passed nothing in the repository secret, it don't work. Please pass.
PAUL: In the class, I have told this part only, no, so many times.
PAUL: Please pass, and don't expose your scene. Guys, don't expose your keys. If somebody…
PAUL: uses that, and they will exhaust it, it becomes a problem. Don't expose the keys, remember.
PAUL: Alright, next.
PAUL: Naga, you are sharing your screen, your issue?
PAUL: Okay, no response.
PAUL: What about others in the panelists?
PAUL: I think, Vojuval, you were asking the question, yes, please listen to Vojuven.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Oh, let me share my screen.
PAUL: Okay, please start.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Okay, I was just trying to ensure that I'm able to, you know, place the project in,
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Langsman.
PAUL: Mmm, here also will be getting the result.
PAUL: Because you have passed that, I think…
PAUL: that API. Blanksmith API. So, yes, here also the tracing should come.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Yeah, I mean, it's, it's… everything is set, and I am able to kind of see the…
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Like, do all the posts and.
PAUL: Local is fine. Local, I know, it will work. What about the part with cloud?
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Yeah, here.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: I don't know why it is not coming, because, if we do a new project, same, all four stuff.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: And then how to…
PAUL: See, what is the issue here? You are not asking questions with respect to deployment, you are asking questions with respect to Langsmith integration is not working in your system. Is that correct?
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Yeah. Yes, that's right.
PAUL: First of all, show me the environment and show me the Langshan version of your PYBI. Harvik, it's completed now, thanks. Alright, Harvik, great.
PAUL: Mohammad Alogare QQ for data science course.
PAUL: For every data science course, I don't start… don't teach starting part, like Python, ML, these things I've never taught.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, after 6 months, that part will come to me.
PAUL: From deep learning. Anything from deep learning, that is my era.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Initially, I think Monol will take the class. Last of which, also, Monol has taken it.
Jainika: Paul, is it essential to understand PyTorch and TensorFlow to move into.
PAUL: This, Virginia, yes.
Jainika: Is it essential?
PAUL: Yes, engineer LLMs comes. So, if you start working with LLMs, it is very, very important.
Jainika: Do we need to understand the concept, or a deep dive into the implementation?
PAUL: A simple concept, if I'm telling you. Now, within the LLM, if I say, like, weights and biases.
PAUL: Now, many people don't understand weights and biases if they have not learned a simple neural network, how they work.
PAUL: Now, the flow, like, simple, like, loss functions, activation functions, which is widely used in transformers, is Jill. Now, people who have worked with ReLU, they will be pretty much comfortable, because they know that this is one type of variant.
PAUL: So, having that fundamental, it's not a lot of things. Scape total computer vision. You don't need to learn anything. But at least the basics, like water loss functions, water activation functions.
PAUL: What are optimizers? What is weight decay? Few concepts are important. If you are doing a quantization operation, if you are doing a fine-tuning operation, everywhere it may come.
Jainika: And from organization point of view, like, my organization is not using, is not working on these, ARAG and AI, they are not using it. So, from industry point of view, so what,
Jainika: what is important? Like, do we need to move ahead to, explore more into fine-tuning our, RAG and,
PAUL: fine-taining less organization will do. It comes with a cost.
PAUL: Like, if it's a research organization, see, product-based companies do it. If it is.
Jainika: What information?
PAUL: nobody.
Jainika: Like, in resume, in service-based also, in resume, like, description, in job description, it has been written, like, fine-tuning model, you shouldn't…
PAUL: general service-based, I have seen the client as a requirement.
PAUL: And if you really tell the client that I want to spend $20,000 just to do some experiment, not every organization agrees on that.
PAUL: Okay, because with fine-tuning, there comes a question that you cannot ignite.
PAUL: Okay, so generally, I don't prefer teaching, because in the next variant of the Ragwatch, I'll be keeping LLMs also.
PAUL: Okay, we're fine-tuning LLM, how to fine-tune SLMs, those things I'll be talking about.
PAUL: But, I feel that it is important that, in media industries, somehow about much more rag that I feel.
PAUL: In India market, I know everybody is working towards RAC, rather than creating LLMs.
PAUL: Everybody is working with LLM. The major task that they do is, basically, they perform a quantization operation on top of your actual LLM to make sure that the hardware on top of which it is running, whether it can do it or not.
Jainika: Will MCPV will also come into the subset of this, like, do we need to understand.
PAUL: It is just, like, an added API stuff, nothing more.
PAUL: MCP is, like, even in your batch also, I'll be talking about MCP. MCP means that how to access the data, through APIs or through your local server calls, through SSC-based events, so those things will come.
PAUL: MCP, really, like, I'm not such a big fan of MCP, but I feel that in some cases, it is helpful, with respect to agentic-based solutions, if you are building. If you're not building agent-based solutions, then it's not so much.
Jainika: Thank you so much.
PAUL: Yes, now, whoever is sharing the screen, like, what is exactly I am looking into, please let me know.
PAUL: Naga, you can stop sharing, because really, there is no audio from your site, and what you are doing.
PAUL: Even there is no reference for me. Which one?
saurabh verma: So, I'm sharing my screen.
PAUL: Joel, you are sharing for.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: I'm sharing my screen.
saurabh verma: Okay.
PAUL: what I'm looking into, tell me.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: This is the main.py, right? Last, like, this is the project.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: So… This is a Q1 day project, not today's one.
PAUL: This has a… it has a few more functionalities, like UI and other stuff, that I… Alright, Janika, we'll go through, alright.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Alright, great, so… How to get this folder here that you are showing on your screen?
PAUL: You don't have to get automatically as get created.
PAUL: Nobody has to do anything, it gets automatically created.
PAUL: In the environment variable, we have to just pass the name.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: I have paused it already, that's what I'm saying, so… It's already here.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Track your production.
PAUL: For Landsmith API key, why you were using those double codes?
PAUL: Don't use double quotes. In my env file, have you seen anywhere double quotes?
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Maybe that's the reason.
PAUL: See, and just check the Langsmith package you have in your system. If the package is not there in your local machine, you will be getting it.
PAUL: Just check that.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Let me check that, yeah.
Ujjawal_Agrawal_ampba2024s@isb.edu: Let me check that, okay, thank you.
Kiran Rathod: Paul, just a query I had. Like, last week's,
Kiran Rathod: repo that we had cloned, right? So, that is only for the reference purpose of the UI, for creating Swagger and all those? Should we follow this current, weeks?
Kiran Rathod: What a full pause.
PAUL: Today's report that I have shared, it was exactly the custom work that we have done.
PAUL: In the Saturday repo, there are a lot of other features. EY was there. Test cases that I have kept. In your CI integration part.
PAUL: Okay, some test cases, generally, like, that is the job of the testing team, but I have kept few test cases for your RAG application.
PAUL: Now, those things have not discussed today.
PAUL: I hope you get my point. Only two things are there. EY, and the other thing is test cases. Those things, I have removed it in this one.
Kiran Rathod: So we need to follow this for complete project.
PAUL: Yes, you can take the reference that the RAT Q&A project is the actual structure. But the core thing, because see, really, test cases, I don't expect everyone to write test cases. That's pretty much separate thing to.
Naga: haven't…
PAUL: Okay, so that's why the UI part, again, you won't be working with UI.
PAUL: Okay, there will be some other team who will be working with that. So, those things which are not your responsibilities, okay, that I have removed from this
PAUL: like, the RAG project report, the class report that we are teaching today.
Kiran Rathod: Okay, so we need to follow up this RAG QA pro… class pro… project class report.
PAUL: Yes, that is for your reference. For example, when you think about build it in a full scale, then yes, you will be including those features also.
Kiran Rathod: Okay.
Kiran Rathod: Got it.
Kiran Rathod: But is it advisable for us to know that at least, at least for a project, an end-to-end completely?
PAUL: That's the purpose, no, I showed you. But UI part, UI, you need to know the UI part.
Naga: You can't believe it now, Ron.
PAUL: It's your job to tell the UI. Now, UI can be built from Lovable also, and you can do the integration. The core job of a data scientist is to build back-end APIs.
PAUL: They don't have to build it. Test cases also, I don't write it. Probably some testing team will do it.
PAUL: So, which is not my responsibility, those things I won't be talking about.
Kiran Rathod: So we'll be building… we'll be building only the core part that was there in the.
PAUL: We are focused only on the EI path.
Kiran Rathod: Okay.
PAUL: Exactly in AI and the deployment part, because here, CI, CT, so many services, those things all will be done.
PAUL: But EY part, really, like, I use wife code, always, to generate EYs.
PAUL: through Lubbable, or that one, because even, like, I'm not a React guy or a Next.js guy.js only…
Kiran Rathod: Yeah, so I'll… yeah, so once the recording is uploaded, then maybe I can go through the recordings for this session, and…
PAUL: Just follow today's session. See, the idea is you take today's report that I have shared and do that. Once you have done that successfully, then pick up that last class that I have shared. There, more things are there. Then you can actually look into what are test cases, how those are written for a RAG application.
Kiran Rathod: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so in that way, it will help you.
Naga: Yeah. Cool.
PAUL: Okay, okay, next.
Naga: Hello, Bron.
PAUL: You have it?
Naga: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
PAUL: Yes, I can hear.
Naga: Paul, sorry, I was talking on mute earlier, sorry about that. But, the thing is, I opened up to the, I built that, Docker, Docker, Docker image.
Naga: And then, I'm trying to run the… this, environment file.
PAUL: Yes, run it.
Naga: It says that, system cannot find the file. Okay, I need to then change that one, because I just poked it, I think, right?
Naga: I think the ENV thing that, and this is one problem, I'll fix this one. Second one was, I was creating the AWS account.
Naga: create, set all this group and all, and then, in the app, services.
PAUL: Yes.
Naga: AWS app runner.
Naga: It's not letting me…
PAUL: Attach your payments. If payment is not enabled.
Naga: Already, already I attached, okay, so…
PAUL: It's telling you, verify your credit card information. It takes time, 24 hours.
Naga: 24 hours with tech time on Thursday.
Naga: So…
PAUL: I had told last week, no, everybody to do the setup.
Naga: Okay, okay, okay. Then… So then, yeah, this ENV file…
Naga: I'll create the ENV file, and ENV file should contain… did you give the sample ENV file here?
PAUL: I think last class report that I have shared, there you have the .knb.example.
Naga: Okay. Okay, I will leave you.
Naga: So, that EME file that we use lost.
Naga: Okay, but, this is what I have done so far, okay?
PAUL: Alright, fine, just say, like, I know this part is tough, go through the recording once your AWS account is available, redo the steps, at least spend today, 2 to 3 days, like, 2 to 3 hours. If it is done today, like, if your AWS accounts get activated, or tomorrow, okay, please do it, because the same workflow will be doing it for our other projects also.
PAUL: GitHub Actions will be there, CI file will be there, deploy file will be there. The standard will be this one. Now, probably after containerization, I might use a different service. Service might change during the deployment, but this will be a certain structure for other projects that we'll maintain.
Naga: Okay, and yeah, GitHub also, it's all done. The secrets I just need to add, okay, this one.
Naga: Yes. Kinda, yeah, so… Yeah, that's the current status for me.
PAUL: Alright, JB, I think you can go ahead.
PAUL: Amit, why we create the IAM user? Actually, see, Amit, the cloud, it's… the idea is that your local should be authenticated with your cloud. So, through that user credentials, I do a local authentication using AWS CLI, and then I can pass all the commands to create a service, delete a service. That is the idea.
saurabh verma: Yeah, so, this has run,
saurabh verma: The Docker build and test, in my case, it has run.
PAUL: Okay, build and test, this is the CI part.
saurabh verma: Yeah, see, iPad, it has run, right?
PAUL: Right?
saurabh verma: Now, my question is, though I will see the recording, my apologies for that. Now, when we go to the code, okay, the next step is for the deploy.
PAUL: Huh.
saurabh verma: Right? So, deploy is there. Now, for the deploy part, you have suggested that we put our names, right?
PAUL: Ha, Madhlav, basically the report that you created, no, we used a command in Notion, like AWS createTCR repository. So, during that, command, when we created the name, the name has to be exactly the same one.
saurabh verma: Yeah, so I, over here, in my, this thing, I have, earlier, during the class, I had created this.
saurabh verma: This one…
PAUL: I'd find.
saurabh verma: QSR.
PAUL: Yes, yeah, this is a manual UYV. I showed you the easy way, one line command, done. You don't need to do any clicks.
saurabh verma: Okay.
saurabh verma: Yeah, yeah, you had given the command, with.
PAUL: Here, also, manually, you can create it in that way.
saurabh verma: Yeah, yeah. So that… those commands are here, like, which we had created, I was running. So these are the things, which had… I had run during the class.
saurabh verma: You remember?
PAUL: Right? AWSCR Describe repo already, it will show you what repo you created.
saurabh verma: So, rack QA system, and this was the… this thing, which.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes, this is correct. According to your UI and the results that you are getting, this is fine.
saurabh verma: Right? So that's why this is there. These are the old ones which were there.
PAUL: Yes.
saurabh verma: So, the next step is, to create the, app service name, right?
saurabh verma: So, when I go over here.
PAUL: No, first, don't create the app runner. First, run that pipeline and see that the image is getting pushed or not. If the image is pushed, then only in AppRunner, you can select.
saurabh verma: Yes, I'm here.
PAUL: image URI. Otherwise, you cannot select it.
saurabh verma: Yeah, so to run that, this thing, now, to run that deploy, what I should do, again, make some changes in README and C.
PAUL: No, no, yes, yes, yes, make a small commit and see.
saurabh verma: Okay.
PAUL: That's why I made it auto. It means that you push the code. For example, you are pushing a new version. Automatically, your CI in CD will trigger.
saurabh verma: Yeah, yeah. So I will just go over here, again, make some changes.
saurabh verma: And now, deploy will run.
PAUL: Yes, yes, just make a commit.
PAUL: Just make a commit, like, git commit.
PAUL: There are 3 commands, always remember.
saurabh verma: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
PAUL: git add dot, git commit hyphen m, the message that you want to pass, and then git push hyphen capital U origin to your branch main.
saurabh verma: I generally use this. ACP, I… with that, I remember ACP add, commit, and push. With that, I…
PAUL: Right? Allow, allow, do, and allow get status.
saurabh verma: Actually, I'm into sales, but I'm learning this so that I can communicate well with the customer, so… my apologies that I have to use.
PAUL: No, fine, fine, I know, like, sales, really, like, from sales, if you're doing this, really.
saurabh verma: I am with 29 years old.
saurabh verma: I've made 29 years of experience.
saurabh verma: Yeah, so… now it should run over here. I go to Workflow.
saurabh verma: It is sunset, it is… the changes have been made and committed.
PAUL: Yeah, and pushed, pushed, pushed.
saurabh verma: So I go over here, right?
PAUL: automatically go to the, RAG project class, the first tab, you will see that your local learn
PAUL: That will come.
saurabh verma: This spring business.
saurabh verma: Test given fail.
PAUL: Click on that.
PAUL: Commit is now? No, no, no, beside that, cross where it's right there. Cross, cross, yes.
PAUL: No, okay, AWS… okay, now, first of all, yes, this pipeline is running, failed after. Look into the first one, because first your CI pipeline will start, just wait.
PAUL: Wheat.
PAUL: Click on that, and the second details.
PAUL: Because this will start… And… Once this will take time.
PAUL: Then just go back to the summary part. I think this part is done only.
saurabh verma: Post Docker build image.
PAUL: Once the image is built.
PAUL: Then it will run the image and do the verification. Exporting layers, alright, so pretty much close to done here.
PAUL: Complete job done. Now go back to summary.
PAUL: go a step at cipipeline.mart.
PAUL: Okay, CI pipeline, go one step back, I think. Read to me, CI, okay. Let it go a step back.
PAUL: Do you have that deploy.yml in your repo?
saurabh verma: Yeah, I am.
PAUL: Go back to, write project class.
PAUL: Because it was failing, yes, click there.
PAUL: Click on that cross, cross where it is written.
PAUL: Okay, and one hour ago, this ECR failing after 6 seconds, click on the details, the first details.
saurabh verma: I think that hybrid name might be a problem, because…
PAUL: Configure AWS credentials. Okay, now this step, it is getting filled. It means that your AWS CLI installation, the local one that you have done, that is not, correct. Okay, so, show me your secrets. Secrets.
PAUL: Secret, yeah, secret.
saurabh verma: I'll go to secure, this is…
PAUL: No, no, no, settings, huh?
saurabh verma: Yeah.
PAUL: Here, you have to pass that, setting, go to Secrets and variables, action.
saurabh verma: Yeah, I had set up all the variables.
PAUL: No.
saurabh verma: I just noticed it.
PAUL: I think in some other repo, we might have done it. In this report, do it again, please.
saurabh verma: Okay, I will set up all the… those various.
PAUL: Yes, yes, because of this…
saurabh verma: It must be…
PAUL: I'm sick.
PAUL: Because it should be there.
saurabh verma: Okay, I'll do it, I'll do it. I'll stop.
PAUL: Because, see, whenever in each step, you will understand that why this step is failing and why it's from the logs.
PAUL: Alright, next, I think JBJB?
PAUL: JB?
JB: Paul, so I have a free version from AWS, can I deploy this, using other features?
PAUL: You need to… in FreeTire, I don't think AppRunner will work. You need to add some credit card. It doesn't come under free tire.
JB: Okay, fine.
JB: Actually, currently, I'm lagging a lot, I'll catch up, I had to go through.
PAUL: Go through the recording, do the steps, because see, these steps, once you have done it successfully.
PAUL: Going forward in the other 4 projects, at least you don't need to focus on the deployment. Probably, I will be changing some service. Services will change, but CI and CD.
PAUL: This will remain exactly the same for everyone. I'm repeating. This is a one-time task, I know, for me also, like, before preparing the content for you, I could do a lot of tests. So, for example, my test might be failing, if I show you.
PAUL: Clean.
PAUL: If I'm telling about my section, so… where is my, I think, yes, this one, yes.
PAUL: So here, rack CT, okay. Before the class, because as I changed my CT script.
PAUL: Okay, so I will just show you, see. Generally, I create a separate branch, and I do my testing there. Yeah, so if you look into this features branch.
PAUL: Okay, even I was, struggling yesterday on, let's say, 13 commits. Actually, this app runner 1, 2, 3, 4, I did even… did multiple changes, and then only it worked for me.
PAUL: Okay, so somewhere it might get stuck. It's a common thing. In CICD, you need time to figure it out, and the learning is at least once, but once you have done it, most of the things will be clear in your mind.
PAUL: Okay, so whenever you look into my repo, you can always look into that even in one shot, for example, if I do a white coding, it is not sure that it will work, but I have to do some manual changes, and based on that, only I can see.
PAUL: Okay, so always look, that's why I create a separate branch and I keep the information.
JB: And so, Paul, so, there must be a trigger for automation, right? So, either it could be CAS, CD,
JB: So.YML contains those figures, right?
PAUL: Yes, correct. So, if I show you my…
PAUL: Here, workflows. So, here I've mentioned the trigger, okay, based on…
PAUL: The build… now, this is the CI part. Here, trigger is not required, this is by default in you. In deploy, I'll be keeping here this workflow dispatch.
PAUL: This is the trigger.
JB: I see.
PAUL: It can be manual, it… you can mention here on push.
PAUL: Okay, so here I have mentioned you can see on push. If I push anything automatically, this particular task will start.
JB: Okay.
PAUL: This is the part with trigger.
JB: Anything similar to this in Langsmith as well?
PAUL: In Landsmith, see, in Landsmith, what they have done, the integration with Landshet. So, probably, they have directly told past it, but somehow, where they are doing the trigger, even I don't have the idea.
PAUL: Really, I have not looked into from where the trigger is coming exactly in the code, because I know, by default, it picks up that. Similarly, if you do it with Lama Intex, then also it picks up. Sorry, I have not checked that part. True to say.
PAUL: Because the core functionality is working, so exactly from where the trigger is coming, really doesn't matter.
JB: So, Paul, this Thursday, you'll be having a call and one more session, right? To take the doubts or something?
PAUL: Doubt immediately have taken today. Tomorrow, I will start Llama Index.
PAUL: Like, tomorrow in the doubt session, you can ask me the similar doubts.
JB: No issues.
JB: Okay, sure, Paul, thank you.
PAUL: Okay, but spend time for everyone. I know this thing is tough, but spend. It's not like in class, you sit for 4 hours, everything. After class, you have to spend more 3 to 6 hours. That is my expectation.
PAUL: From this course, it's not like that. 3 hours come, some spoon-pitting done. Not possible, guys. You have… every day, at least, you are putting 1 hour… 1 hour, at least.
PAUL: If somebody is in advanced level, I know a few students are there who can easily get it, because they have attended, like, two batches, three batches of our different cohorts. It's easier for them to adapt. If somebody is totally new into this cohort, it will be, and directly as this is an advanced course.
PAUL: you will be having the problems. In other courses, in Project 1, nobody teaches CICT.
PAUL: Only in this project I have started then.
PAUL: in your syllabus also that I mentioned CICT, because going forward in Project 2, 3, 4, you should not have that particular problem.
PAUL: Okay, because so many things to learn from this, like, if somebody doesn't know about Docker.
PAUL: go and learn about Docker. Spend at least, one hour. There is a… so many YouTube videos are there. Okay, pick up something from Kresh, or pick up something from DevOps, like, I think Tech with Nana is there. Nana, she's also a great creator. Okay, you can directly look into that, or I think that, one is also there.
PAUL: That, dubai guy. Okay, so, pick up. So, at least spend 1 hour.
PAUL: Okay, and then keep a Docker cheat sheet with it.
PAUL: So that you will become used to the commands which is widely used, like Docker PSA, hyphen A, Docker images. So to use the Docker Cheat Sheet, you will be getting it. So, for example.
PAUL: For DevOps, for every tool, you'll be having a cheat sheet.
PAUL: Okay, you can see the official from the Docker docs will be getting this cheat sheet. Just keep it open, keep it somewhere, so that you are familiar with the commands. I use these commands, I am totally used to this, but you might not be.
PAUL: See, after that comes the AWS part.
PAUL: If you're not familiar with the service, like these containers, but you need to keep the images from your local. I've not shown any other deployment.
PAUL: The easier one, but going forward, I'll be showing you some others also, like, which is very, very easy. You're directly using Lightning, or some other product.
PAUL: Okay, so spend some time. I know that everybody might not be knowing about Docker, but at least spend.
PAUL: Because in the last class, also, like, 3 people told I am not familiar with FastAPI and Pydantic. I've taken that extra session, and I have told. But for every topic, you cannot ask me that Paul take an extra session for this topic.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why. Spend some time, at least take. My expectation is that after the class, or after 2 classes, you are spending 5 to 6 hours.
PAUL: Okay, for everyone, please go through this.
PAUL: I mean, in your company, if Docker is blocked, okay, then try to use some other environment for your entire development job. Some browser-based, like Lightning, I've already told you previously.
PAUL: Alright. Right.
PAUL: AWS will become more clear, as in our other classes also, we'll be talking about AWS a lot.
PAUL: Prashant is telling Prashant Manuhar, you are facing some issues, and I'm gonna…
Santosh Umargi: Paul,
PAUL: bookcase.
PAUL: Service is running and ready for me, great summer.
Santosh Umargi: Paul, but, like, while I'm, doing the API call, no one, it is failing, like, internal server error.
PAUL: Measuring document.
Santosh Umargi: Yup. Sure.
Santosh Umargi: I think we had to upload the document from fresh here also, again.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no, no, doesn't matter.
Santosh Umargi: Okay.
PAUL: Show me the application part.
Santosh Umargi: Yo.
Santosh Umargi: See, this completed, it has given the health check, no? It is working fine.
Santosh Umargi: And once I go to docs, no?
PAUL: Hmm.
Santosh Umargi: So, it is loading. So, here, no, suppose… here, no, any document is there at first, right?
Santosh Umargi: It is a fresh, right?
PAUL: No, no, no, I think last time, at the last class, you uploaded your documents, no.
Santosh Umargi: No, no, actually, last time also, I think, that's what, some, last time I missed, like, that's why I picked the old repo, no? Oh, that's why.
PAUL: Okay, now, my idea was that last time you have pushed something, some video.
Santosh Umargi: No, no.
PAUL: If you have not pushed it, try to push it now, and just look into there, no, we will look into the application loans.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, okay. So this, this, this thing I pushed, like, I think it doesn't have any document, huh? This, this site made the…
PAUL: No, I asked any PDF that you feel, whichever you have in your local system, at least push.
Santosh Umargi: Okay.
Santosh Umargi: So, like, upload now, right?
PAUL: Prashant, do you want to share your screen? Please let me know, I will add you to panelist Prashant.
Prasath Manohar: Yes, Paul, can you…
PAUL: You declined the request, that's why I thought.
PAUL: Okay, I'm adding you to panelist, accept the request.
PAUL: Any PDF file that you fill.
Santosh Umargi: Yeah.
PAUL: Okay, now let's see what is the error that you are getting at here.
PAUL: Incorrect API key.
Santosh Umargi: Okay.
Santosh Umargi: This is… it is saying about OpenAI API, right?
PAUL: Correct.
Santosh Umargi: But I fetched from the platform only, yeah. I'm using that for other projects. Okay, let me check, I will check that, yeah.
PAUL: Okay. So I have to change this, in the service only, or, like, in the service only, no, if suppose key is formed? You have to change it in GitHub Secrets.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, GitHub secret, and then I reboot.
PAUL: Before changing it to GitHub Secrets, first of all, check that in your local it's working or not.
Santosh Umargi: Okay.
PAUL: Your local… first of all, your local application is up and working. Once the local application is working, create the Docker, and then check the Docker image is working or not, the container that will be running. Once the container is running, then only move to the part with AWS.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, okay, got it, yeah.
PAUL: Perfect.
Santosh Umargi: Okay.
Santosh Umargi: Thank you.
saurabh verma: Yeah, so in my case, I updated the credentials, I'll show that again.
PAUL: Prasam, please start sharing.
PAUL: Yes, hon.
Prasath Manohar: Yep.
Prasath Manohar: Paul, can you see my screen?
PAUL: Yes, Vashant. You have to do a rerun for it.
Prasath Manohar: In my case, I pushed the container, but still I'm getting this error during the Deploy-to-app runner.
PAUL: Okay, show me, from the UI, the images available once.
PAUL: No, no, no, EY. AWS.
PAUL: AWS, okay. Yes, manually, we created this particular…
Prasath Manohar: Let me share the complete screen in just a minute.
PAUL: Hmm.
Prasath Manohar: Do you see my AWS?
PAUL: No, I see your other notion, and I think user guide, you're that one.
Prasath Manohar: Sorry.
Prasath Manohar: Give me a minute.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Alright, once, Saurabh, you have passed the cigarettes, try to push and see now what is the error you were getting.
saurabh verma: Yeah, so these were the keys that I had set, and when I go to Actions.
PAUL: Okay, Amit, see, like, I used to use double quotes to say, but after that, I have really stopped using double quotes. I feel that double quotes is not required whenever you are working with the package. See, double quotes also works.
PAUL: Like, I never face any problem with double quotes, but manually you have to add it every time. That's the only thing, whereas directly also we can pass according to the official documentation that is provided.
PAUL: Okay, so both the things are fine.
PAUL: Yes, please, boss.
saurabh verma: Yeah, so then I clicked on this.
PAUL: Because right now, I can see only your ExpressVPN window.
Prasath Manohar: Oops.
PAUL: How many monitors you are connected with?
Prasath Manohar: Sorry, yeah.
PAUL: All right, fine, yes.
PAUL: Now, in this one, I can see… okay, now click on Browse.
PAUL: Yes, choose the repo that you created, see.
PAUL: Where is the report?
Prasath Manohar: It says it's pushed, right? Built and pushed, sorry.
PAUL: No, no, no, see, pushes for the image, but where the push take place?
PAUL: For the repo. So, first of all, you should have a repo, no? I told you to create a repo. For that, I shared the command in Notion.
Prasath Manohar: Okay, fine, I will check that, yeah, I will check and get back.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Fresh…
saurabh verma: shunt, okay.
PAUL: Fair enough.
saurabh verma: Yeah, Paul, are you able to see my screen?
PAUL: Yes, yes, I can.
PAUL: So…
saurabh verma: Should I.
PAUL: Rerun, rerun, rerun, rerun. Rerun jobs, rerun, on the top, top, top, top, top, top, top, top, right-hand side, right-hand side, top, rerun jobs. Okay? Rerun, failed jobs, failed, failed, failed, yes. Let me see.
PAUL: Build and push to ECR, that part is failing, so let's see what's… token invalid,
PAUL: showing in sort of screen. Token invalid, okay, I will come. Okay, in the first step, only it failed. It means that the verification.
PAUL: Okay, click on… Build and push to easier.
PAUL: Okay, and now I'll see,
PAUL: security token included in the request is invalid. It's simply telling that your credentials are invalid.
PAUL: Show me your credentials now, one by one.
PAUL: Yeah, really, like, if you even pass a white space, then also an error will come.
saurabh verma: Oh, you know…
PAUL: You have to be very much careful.
saurabh verma: So, I will…
PAUL: AWS access key ID. Okay, just paste those things again. I think it will be in your clipboard, no? Yes.
saurabh verma: Yeah, here it is.
PAUL: After the class, please delete this user.
saurabh verma: Yeah.
PAUL: Somehow, if there is an admin access, no, anybody can do anything.
PAUL: Very dangerous thing.
PAUL: Verify via mail, okay, fine, do it, verify.
PAUL: Generally, a verification is required with the passkey. Generally, I use that Fingerprint.
saurabh verma: Okay, so I have to see in my email, right?
PAUL: ESC in your email, you will be getting that code, just paste that.
saurabh verma: Yeah, yeah, it's… I'll just check one with my screen.
PAUL: You can export, yes, you can do an export.
PAUL: But not import directly.
PAUL: Again, like, for GitHub also, you do have a CLI version. Through GitHub CLI, those things that can be done.
PAUL: I'll just stop sharing and edit all the keys. Okay, yes, that will be better.
PAUL: Okay, JB?
PAUL: I think you have raised your hand, I think that is done.
PAUL: Okay, I will lower the handle.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, for everyone.
PAUL: Again, I am repeating, spend some time today or tomorrow. Like, if your AWS account is not ready, after 24 hours, once your account is ready, spend time on this one.
PAUL: I feel that this is a good activity from your interview prospect also, at least you will have something.
PAUL: Okay, with respect to deployment.
PAUL: exactly what are the services which have been used. Now, going forward, we'll be using much more services, like, this is easier. Similarly, I can pick up EBS, I can pick up Farget. In that way, I'll be just changing the service from AWS. The core internal logic, CI and CD, they will remain the same.
PAUL: Yes, Anthosh, delete the service, app runner service. For rep, you don't get charged, but again, you won't be using the image, delete that also.
PAUL: Delete the report, delete the app runner. Again, I am repeating, for this class, if app runner gets switched on, you will get a bill. If you see after 7 days, you will see 300 to 400 rupees charged to your account.
PAUL: more RAM and more… if you have taken 4GB of RAM, that bill will come close to 1500.
PAUL: please be sure that you have deleted or killed those services. From the terminal, I've given you the terminal commands. Not comfortable, open the AWS UI console. From there, delete it.
PAUL: So nobody should tell me, Paul, I got charged after one month.
PAUL: Okay, 20,000 rupees.
PAUL: That happens in every batch, and there is one such student I know who will come with that.
PAUL: Okay, so in every batch, there is one. At least one has to be there.
saurabh verma: So, Paul, how do I do rerun? I have set the credentials again.
PAUL: You have, again, then, just the workflow which paid deploy to AWS, click on that.
PAUL: I think here you have, you have to rerun the workflow.
PAUL: Yes, from their run workflow.
PAUL: Because it will pick up again, I think.
PAUL: Just wait. It takes time.
PAUL: Actually, like, when you do a complete run workflow, so… Now it has taken notes. When I click on this?
PAUL: Here he is.
PAUL: Please do click on that.
saurabh verma: I think it has passed, otherwise it would have failed by now.
saurabh verma: In 7 seconds, it had…
PAUL: you'll just click on that.
PAUL: We will see the phase. If that particular phase has passed, he has configured login to done.
saurabh verma: So, it was the white space in hurry which got added.
PAUL: That's why, that white spaces. Like, for every student in other batches also I've seen, that's a common error.
saurabh verma: But really, great class, you are taking a lot of effort, I'm enjoying it.
PAUL: These things are really, like, advanced also. It means that if somebody is a beginner, if they expect, like, it becomes very tough for them to adapt also.
PAUL: like, that's why the… if somebody has a good Python…
PAUL: At least for foundation, it becomes easier, but at least for Python guys also, somebody's doing it for first time. That's why I'm teaching you all the hard stuff in the first time only, because in other projects, I don't have to do so much hard work. Now, see, it's telling that the repo with the name rack.
saurabh verma: Wow.
PAUL: So, what is the name that you have passed, please pass that.
saurabh verma: Yeah, yeah, I got it, because this you had told that we need to put in our case, in the deploy, I need to remove the hybrid.
PAUL: No, no, no, see, ECR repo, if here, hybrid is there, it's fine. Check, like, your ECR, what is your OpenAWS UI?
saurabh verma: Yeah, yeah, I'm going there.
PAUL: Okay, go to the ECR service.
PAUL: Now see what name you have given here. You are given right to enter systems. That same name has to be there.
saurabh verma: Yeah.
saurabh verma: Whoa.
saurabh verma: I'll go here.
saurabh verma: Okay.
PAUL: Do an F.
PAUL: Controllers, this you have to push, then only it will be recognized, no?
PAUL: AppRanner, yes, we manually created it, and then we updated it.
PAUL: Permit.
PAUL: Only for that ECR access role, I created it. Otherwise, through command line also, you can do the same thing, creating the access role.
PAUL: But for that, you have to create a .json file, few more steps, so directly I shoot it from the UI.
PAUL: In future, no. Like, the secret doesn't come automatically in AppRun, so at least you need to pass it manually or through an update.
PAUL: So that's why, like, we didn't pass the environment file, but through an update, it gets automatically updated.
saurabh verma: I have, pulled the changes back. So, again, it will run CIC.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes, again, it will shut.
PAUL: After every push, CIMC. That is the idea. Like, in production, this way, only it happens.
saurabh verma: So this is happening right now.
saurabh verma: No, you believe that.
PAUL: Click on Update Workflow, yes.
PAUL: you will see the first step, build and push tools here. Click on that.
PAUL: Hmm. I'll see, like…
PAUL: Login to ECR is done, you can see now these steps have started. Build, tag, and push. So right now the build phase is going on.
PAUL: Ahmed, can we automate this push and commit automatically? It is already configured, no. Whenever you push anything to GitHub, automatically the deployment will start.
saurabh verma: It is run.
saurabh verma: Now, debit…
PAUL: deployment on which, well, in that case, you have to take care, see, just select one branch, and on top of that, you can apply some cron jobs. So, only one branch from there.
PAUL: Then that way it's been doing.
PAUL: Manually. And even in here, also, you can do it based on a date, time, exactly when we want to repeat those things. Those things can be automated.
PAUL: Which one?
saurabh verma: So, Paul, good news is that it has pushed. Now, as we know, that first time it will fail, right?
PAUL: Deploy to AppRunner will fail. Go back, click on deploy to AppRunner, just look into the error.
PAUL: From errors, you'll measure the learning. See, if it doesn't exist. Click on that, Click on that.
saurabh verma: Yeah, Clint.
PAUL: Okay, now you will see something. It's telling that, okay, access role, invalid length for parameter configuration, authentication configuration, access role, valid minimum length 29, alright. Now, just go back to your app runner service.
PAUL: Okay, so till now, you have not created any, service here. Okay, now click on Browse. You will see that image will be available. That queue vendor system.
saurabh verma: I need to refresh, I think so.
PAUL: Okay, just do a page refresh here.
PAUL: Okay, now select. Automatically, the latest tag will come.
saurabh verma: Yeah, it should go.
saurabh verma: Yeah.
PAUL: Okay, Ken. Continue.
PAUL: Okay, now scroll down.
PAUL: Okay, create new, create new, click on next.
saurabh verma: Next.
saurabh verma: And in the file also, I need to change the deploy file.
PAUL: Topsy.
saurabh verma: etc.
PAUL: service name, past the exact service name which is mentioned in your deploy.yml.
saurabh verma: Yeah, this isn't…
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes.
PAUL: Alright, go below.
saurabh verma: Let's likely to check more spaces here.
PAUL: Okay, yes, now click on next.
PAUL: Okay, now you can see your ECR access rule. Copy this information and paste it in your GitHub Secrets.
saurabh verma: Which one? This one?
PAUL: Deployment settings, right-hand side, ECR access role. ECR access role. Yes, that you have to copy and paste it in your GitHub secrets.
saurabh verma: GitHub Secrets, yeah, yeah, yeah. I got it.
saurabh verma: That is the first, in Notion which we have shared, the first.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes, the first variable.
saurabh verma: Yeah, yes, I agree with that.
saurabh verma: Settings…
saurabh verma: I'll need to change the…
PAUL: First, paste the secret, and then get the… Paste the secret, right? You copied it, no?
PAUL: Yes, get that.
saurabh verma: To copy, I'll again copy that.
saurabh verma: this?
PAUL: Mmm, now the secret.
saurabh verma: Let's see.
PAUL: add secret.
saurabh verma: Yeah.
saurabh verma: Now go to the question, and rerun.
PAUL: I think, go back to Aprana.
PAUL: Apprait. You have to click on…
saurabh verma: Ebrenner, yeah.
PAUL: And now go below, click on next.
PAUL: Created deployment that option.
saurabh verma: Major step.
PAUL: Now, once the application will be deployed here, then, like, the service is created, so automatically your environment variables, all those things will be picked up from the script. So, again, you have to do one more commit.
PAUL: And then it will be updated. So this service takes time close to 2 to 5 minutes, so after 2 to 5 minutes, you can do a new commit, and then…
saurabh verma: Okay.
PAUL: The deployment will be done, yes.
saurabh verma: Right, I'll do that. Okay. Thank you very much.
PAUL: Holdrick, sort of.
saurabh verma: You can remove me, you know, from the panel.
PAUL: And I think no others out there.
PAUL: So, everyone, so tomorrow, we will start with Lama Intex. So, this part, the project one, just… everyone should be good with Project 1, that everything you know in detail, if you have anything, please let me know tomorrow, okay, or in the future classes, if you get stuck.
saurabh verma: Paul, I have one request. Yes. Paul, I have one request. Though you are taking, you and Krish all are taking advanced classes like this, but in future, if you can please take the class for Git and Docker and Kubernetes also, it will be a big help. I'm telling you…
saurabh verma: I know there are many, there are many YouTube materials and all that, but now we have got used to your learning, learning from you.
PAUL: Actually, you see, like, Kubernetes, we never teach it in any batch. Everywhere we'll be showing you the application. Each Kubernetes tech.
saurabh verma: That's okay, but Git and Docker, if you can teach separately, you know, or YouTube, you paid classes, if there are theirs, you know.
PAUL: Git part, see, Git part, generally, I do it from the UI most of the times to VS Code. From the terminal, I can pass the main commands only. Few things are there that manually also I can do in some other projects.
PAUL: like, git commit hyphen, and that way I can write it. But at least, like, see, I know for the git lecture, I don't remember just with.
PAUL: In every batch, we do share those information before the starting in the introduction phase.
saurabh verma: Yeah, you share, but, like, how you take these classes, one by one, you are taking the steps, so we also then execute. So that makes a big difference. Others don't do that.
saurabh verma: This requires a lot of patience, which you all are taking.
PAUL: That's what I think, where I think in this one, I have kept it somewhere in here.
PAUL: Our app is there, GCP, I think, somewhere. Yes, the Docker is also there.
PAUL: Somewhere I might keep gate also, gate also, gate and GitHub.
PAUL: Yeah, share these resources.
saurabh verma: In the Notion, in the current project notion, if you can share, it will be a big help.
PAUL: Okay, this page… I have not added it through that checklist. Just wait, let me attach this page here.
PAUL: Okay, this… okay, this is the other software checklist. You have already, no?
PAUL: Check, check. It's there, the software checklist.
saurabh verma: Okay, okay. I'll check in there.
PAUL: Okay, Amit is telling I clicked on upgrade plan, and it's showing yes, generally, like, it is not available in free time. Once you have to do that upgrade, then only afternoon will be available. Many services, like EKAs, if we are going. I think in one of the projects, EKAs also mentioned.
PAUL: Okay, so in those cases, you need an upgraded account in free tax.
PAUL: We cannot do everything in this course, even for Bedrock and for multiple services, we need a paid account.
PAUL: All right, guys, so I will be concluding the session, then, for today. Thank you. Let's meet tomorrow. Tomorrow's agenda, Llama Index. Okay, so we'll be talking with… yes?
saurabh verma: Next weekend, is there any class, or it is holiday?
PAUL: No, no, next token there will be class.
saurabh verma: Everything is okay.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: All my schedule is a little bit different, that's why, like…
PAUL: my one… two-month holiday is done in October and November. Once your batch started, I have to do all things that way.
saurabh verma: Okay, okay, no problem. Thank you.
PAUL: Okay, alright, I'd like to create the apprah now. Alright, Rashant, fine. Okay, so everybody, for whoever is not done, please spend some time.
PAUL: Okay, go through the lecture once the recording is available, spend tonight at least 2 hours, because tomorrow, again, the agenda will change, but I can take questions with respect to your deployment issue tomorrow also. So just be sure. Wherever you are stuck, please take an attempt by yourself, it is not getting resolved, let me know tomorrow.
PAUL: Bye-bye, everyone, thanks for joining.